<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Arturo Negrette</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Arturo Negrette</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Project SABR</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/rde.png" alt="Featured image of post Project SABR" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-achievements&#34;&gt;Major Achievements:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Developed a fully-fledged testing platform for air-breathing RDEs at UCF&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Laid the foundation for a future senior design teams&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Produced data for several AIAA SciTech 2025 papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rotating Detonation Engines (RDEs) are a relatively novel form of rocket propulsion that takes advantage of pressure-gain combustion. Conventional rocket engines use constant-pressure combustion cycles. RDEs theoretically produce better performance by taking better advantage of the energy stored chemically in the propellants. There is a fine line between detonating in the way that yields the performance advantage, and detonating in the way that destroys the engine. Due to the speeds involved in the process, these engines have only recently began gaining traction now that computers and sensors allow for the extremely fast sampling rates necessary for reliable data output. Their compact size allows for storable propellants to be used more effectively in missile and defense applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals of this project at the beginning were beyond creating a working air breathing lab scale engine, to lay the foundation for further research to be done at UCF. This involved creating a test stand equipped with a capable and robust data acquisition system and control system. With the tight budget for a project of this ambition we had to get creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ignition&#34;&gt;Ignition
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lighting an RDE involves precise timing and a strong enough relese of energy to induce a detonation mode within the engine. A fast burst (in tens of micro seconds) with not a lot of energy is more likely to induce a detonation compared to a longer burst with a ton more energy. Typically predets are used where an explosive mixture of gases are lit on one end of a long tube and over that length of tube the energy release is structured in such a way a shock is developed by the time the combusting gases exit. Due to the mechanism of operation, these have careful geometry that is hard to package into a system with compact and flight in mind. This is where my approach comes in, conventional torch. If the annulus can act as the constriction that focuses the energy towards a shock, the igniter can be more compact and allow for smaller designs for flight vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
<<<<<<< HEAD
&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of both mechanical and electrical aspects of the ignition system. In terms of the mechanical side of things, I prioritized cost and ease of manufacturing over anything else, arriving at what is essentially a modified stainless steel 1/4 NPT cross fitting, as pictured below. The torch body is then connected to the rest of the RDE via a thick-walled stainless steel pipe nipple. I truly didn&amp;rsquo;t want the torch to be plagued by scope creep, so it incorporates as much stuff off the shelf as I could find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, the electrical system employs a standard car ignition coil, the cheapest I could find on Amazon. The circuit puts a 12V SPDT relay in purgatory by switching it rapidly between powering its own coil and pulsing the primary of the ignition coil. Additionally, a couple capacitors and resistors finetune exactly how long the charging and discharging takes in order to ensure the primary winding of the ignition coil has time to fully saturate before the power is switched off and the fields collapse to generate the high voltage out of the secondary. I could&amp;rsquo;ve gone with something based on a 555 timer or even more fancy, but circling back to that thought about scope creep, I truly just wanted it to work and work without needing to think about it. The only drawback is that mechanical relays really don&amp;rsquo;t like being switched that fast, and because the coil within the relay is also an inductor, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of arcing when it&amp;rsquo;s disconnected during the cycling. Adding a flyback diode across reduced the switching frequency so I arrived at the conclusion that relays are cheap enough to be consumable. During testing, the poor little relay did not fail or weld itself shut once, but if I were to be pulled back to the drawing board for a proper vehicle-born ignition system, I&amp;rsquo;d probably choose to go with something solid state or capacitor-based much like modern cars use for their sparking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cheeky extra feature I added to the torch is the presence of a pressure transducer line. During startup,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 inch enough to protect it, reduces its response time&lt;/p&gt;
=======
&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of both mechanical and electrical aspects of the ignition system. In terms of the mechanical side of things, I prioritized cost and ease of manufacturing over anything else, arriving at what is essentially a modified stainless steel 1/4 NPT cross fitting, as pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The torch body is then connected to the rest of the RDE via a thick-walled stainless steel pipe nipple.&lt;/p&gt;
>>>>>>> ad30d4e13d88badee40cd9332bf4cc930bc1e7d5
&lt;p&gt;In practice, the concept of lighting the RDE was a lot easier said than done. I go more into detail about the outcome under Testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before pivoting towards my work in ignition, I helped with the first handful of iterations of the combustor. I focused on packaging and routing alongside my buddy Hunter, essentially figuring out how to efficiently route propellants from their respective ports coming from the fluids system and into the injectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we weighed the our options for manufacturing methods. We could push for an additively manufactured design, which would allow for complex geometry and reduce the number of critical seals to worry about, but had the drawback of very money, timeline, and risk intensive. On the other hand, we could go for something doable with the resources available at the UCF Machine Shop: reliable and free access to 3 and 5 axis machining, turning, EDM hole drilling and wire cutting. All we&amp;rsquo;d have to source is our required material. Regardless of whether we printed it or machined it conventionally, the RDE would be exposed to extreme conditions surrounding the detonation wave as it propagates, which means high pressures and temperatures sweeping around in a circle. Compared to a conventional engine, the cyclic failure modes began rearing their ugly head in all of our analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe_hu_7e021c70bed04496.gif 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe_hu_6b6678d8315ef4f4.gif 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Transient conditions within the combustor. Source: Wikipedia&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only saving grace was that the timescales for all this energy release were minuscule, although they compounded over time. Based on the fact we were targetting a very short runtime of only a couple seconds (and much more engineering analysis I will not go into here), we decided to go for 304 Stainless Steel. The reasoning came down to the fact we wanted the ability to fail and iterate without being dead in the water trying to source another brick of material to machine or a whole new printed part. Much of the research behind RDEs is uncharted territory, so even with all of our calculations and analysis double, triple, and quadruple checked, we wanted a large margin of safety on top of the ability to return to the drawing board and modify our design without crippling the project. So with all that being said, we settled on a conventionally manufactured combustor. From all the discussion, preliminary analysis, and talking to researchers both at UCF labs and across the US in places like Purdue and Johns Hopkins, we went for a modular design based on a stack of plates. Below are some of the first iterations of our combustor, initially by me and later modified by Hunter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE.png&#34;
	width=&#34;723&#34;
	height=&#34;838&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE_hu_c31bd0cecbc05a2e.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE_hu_dd98a65c6c29eab3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The First Assembly of the Project&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;86&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;207px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu.png&#34;
	width=&#34;626&#34;
	height=&#34;643&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu_hu_2a400445cfc86f5c.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu_hu_1746674ed0027766.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A section view better showing our initial plenum design&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;97&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;233px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount.png&#34;
	width=&#34;405&#34;
	height=&#34;297&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount_hu_f029b252b05fe1d3.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount_hu_f18d0d9e6e596db3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Combustor in context of its thrust-bearing mounting plate&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;136&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;327px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great start, but with any engineering project, we quickly started spotting flaws in terms of component integration, manufacturing, and especially in terms of final assembly in the stand. Looking back while writing this knowing how the project turned out as a whole makes the original design look extra alien.&lt;/p&gt;
<<<<<<< HEAD
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the combustor consisted of an inner and outer body, nozzle cowl and spike, and the injector plate and backing plate. The inner and outer body constrain the annulus dimensions and their negative space form the cavity where the combustion occurs. The inner body, however, also acts as part of the internal plenum for one of the propellants. The selected injector schema is &amp;ldquo;Jet-in-Crossflow&amp;rdquo;. As the name implies, one of the propellants is injected perpendicular to the other. In our case, the hydrogen flows radially out from the inner body as the air is injected longitudinally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the nozzle spike and cowl, we decided on constricting the opening at the end of the annulus to raise the static pressure after the propellants are injected, as it has the effect of increasing detonability and aiding in ignition. It ensures propellants remain within the chamber for longer, which also helps the process overall.&lt;/p&gt;
=======
&lt;p&gt;Plate design after ruling out 3d printing due to timeline and thankfully tariffs confirmed out option&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to route taps for pressure and igniter channel using conventional machining methods&lt;/p&gt;
>>>>>>> ad30d4e13d88badee40cd9332bf4cc930bc1e7d5
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rest-of-it&#34;&gt;The Rest Of It
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would love to keep writing much more about all that this project entailed, but it ultimately was a deeply intertwined group contribution. I am highlighting my direct work on getting this RDE off the ground, so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to any of my teammates to mention it all without also highlighting their achievements. A major part of senior design at UCF are these &amp;ldquo;Milestone Reports&amp;rdquo; where we, as a team, got together and tracked our work in a format similar to a design review. Milestone 6, the final one, contains a snapshot of the past year of our work leading up to the results we got and how we&amp;rsquo;d improve upon our work if we were to hypothetically continue testing after the semester ended. I feel it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to provide a curious reader, perhaps someone looking to base their research on our work, with the necessary in-depth info about the combustor, test stand, and our results. Please reach out to me directly if you have any questions. Email is best, all available over on the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/rdereport.pdf&#34; &gt;Here it is, weighing in at 134 pages.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go along with the report, I&amp;rsquo;d also like to provide a quick slidestack that we used to give an overview about the project. I can&amp;rsquo;t embed it as a .pptx, so unfortunately, gifs will not work on this version. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/showcaseslides.pdf&#34; &gt;Showcase Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to still cover what we experienced taking the design from a whiteboard/Solidworks to a real, working prototype. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be covering my contribution to our combined in-the-field problem solving and troubleshooting. Just know it&amp;rsquo;ll all be in a very simplified manner because, after all, we wrote that document precisely to act as a self-contained reference guide to our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing&#34;&gt;Testing
<<<<<<< HEAD
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Igniter shattering, startup transient for igniter difficult to predict&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-design-showcase&#34;&gt;Senior Design Showcase
=======
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-design-showcase&#34;&gt;Senior Design Showcase
>>>>>>> ad30d4e13d88badee40cd9332bf4cc930bc1e7d5
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/srb3Dv_vAVQ&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts-and-acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts and Acknowledgements
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thicker annulus, overestimated pressures, ignition may be easier with the torch, testing necessary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;things id fix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;better thrust calibration, possibly using a pneumatic/hydraulic cylinder to calibrate load cells&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;less rigid plumbing, alternatively, put the whole thrust bearing frame on linear bearings, measure thrust there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank and congratulate Dr. Rezzag-Lebza, Dr. Burke, Dr. Stresau, and of course, my teammates. All our hard work paid off, and I hope we left a solid foundation for future detonation combustion research at UCF for both future senior design teams and researchers. Additionally, all the work before us that inspired the project as a whole: Fiorino, Dechert, among the many researchers across the US pioneering RDEs as a platform for future vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a machinist, I&amp;rsquo;d also like to highlight the crucial role that UCF&amp;rsquo;s Office of Research Machine Shop played in helping us not only bring the project to life, but also playing a role as a major contributor in optimizing the manufacturability of our system. The latter, along with their hard work, allowed us to achieve a quick turnaround between iterations. We were able to go from testing and reviewing data to firing a modified engine in the span of a week. Reader, remember to thank your manufacturing team as often as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Project Pegasus</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/project-pegasus/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/project-pegasus/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/pegasuscover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Project Pegasus" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-achievements&#34;&gt;Major Achievements:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pioneered a novel fuel grain composition.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Solved emulsification problems between fuel grain ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Developed an modular injector plate, allowing for quick refurbishment in case of damage.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Generated manufacturing procedures to guarantee repeatability and uniformity between fuel grain batches.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Successfully static fired twice, both times gaining N-class impulse classification, outperforming previous generations by 60% in peak thrust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was my first major project in college, and I was in the position to spearhead an approach to hybrids that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been tried before at UCF. At this point, I had messed around with Paraffin-based fuels on my own small backyard hybrid, but I encountered the typical issues with density, structural stability, and burn stability as every other amateur. I came into this project with the goal of finding a solution to these issues by dedicating a major part of the year to R&amp;amp;D and testing every single approach we could come up with, the Skunkworks Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the previous hybrid projects at UCF all incorporated pyrotechnic valves, with zero control of oxidizer flow after ignition starts. I took it as a challenge to incorporate basic valve control to allow for finetuning of the burn, and most importantly, lay out the framework for in-flight burn control. The importance of being able to control how the motor performs during the flight comes from the ability to pinpoint the target apogee and maximize the points scored within the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-paraffin-problem&#34;&gt;The Paraffin Problem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, paraffin has its issues, but what are its upsides?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for a fuel to burn, it needs to first become a gas in order to react with the oxidizer, much like gasoline vapors are the part that actually burns. In hybrids, depending on the fuel, this mechanism can occur in two different ways, which allows us to separate fuels into two major categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plastic/Rubber (HTPB, ABS, any kind of epoxy, resins, etc.)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
For these, there&#39;s no intermediate phase.  Solid immediately turns into gas for combustion. These tend to be more energy dense, stable, and easier to handle. Downside comes down to mixing efficiency.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Paraffins&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
Paraffin has the unique trait of having an intermediate phase, where it turns into liquid before gasifying when burning. This allows it to develop an unstable liquid layer that flings droplets into the oxidizer stream, giving it an advantage when it comes to energy release and burn efficiency. However, it tends to be softer, prone to cracking, and carries a much lower energy density compared to the others. &lt;b&gt;Also, it won&#39;t withstand much time in the New Mexico Desert during the summer.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we could solve paraffin&amp;rsquo;s issues, we&amp;rsquo;d have a great middle ground with room for growth in future projects. My first instinct was to research candlemaking forums, books and every other piece of media I could get my hands on. As a society, we&amp;rsquo;ve been making candles for centuries and have grown pretty good at it. As it turns out, different waxes can increase paraffin&amp;rsquo;s structural stability, melting point, hardness, and alleviate shrinkage/cracking issues. All this research led me towards adding Microcrystalline Wax and Stearic Acid to provide these benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final problem comes down to energy density, and this is where Sorbitol comes in. It&amp;rsquo;s a cheap, plentiful diet sugar replacement that&amp;rsquo;s extensively used in amateur solid rocket motors, as well as some hybrids. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to melt and very resilient towards caramelization, which reduces sugar fuels&amp;rsquo; performance. At this point, we came across the age old problem of trying to mix oil with water. See, paraffin is polar and sorbitol is non-polar, meaning we&amp;rsquo;re ending up with a block split into two layers when everything cools down. &lt;b&gt;Suboptimal.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where emulsifiers come in. Mayo, for example, is oil and water mixed together, but no one thinks of two layers when thinking of mayo. See, in order for something like that to remain homogeneous, you need a third ingredient in order to &amp;ldquo;interface&amp;rdquo; between the two substances and keep them happy next to each other. In the case of mayonnaise, it&amp;rsquo;s egg. In the case of our fuel mixture? We tried commercial grade emulsifiers and surfactants, Sodium Laureth Sulfate, namely. Pretty similar stuff to shampoo components. Ultimately we arrived at a super high-tech solution: &lt;b&gt;Dawn Dish Soap with Papaya Scent.&lt;/b&gt; Remember, if it&amp;rsquo;s stupid and it works then it&amp;rsquo;s not stupid. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how effective a tiny bit of Dawn was at homogeinizing the ingredients and keeping them together when everything cooled back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more issue I wanted to solve wasn&amp;rsquo;t really critical but instead a way to appease my lizard brain desire to push past 100%. In order to extract more performance out of this fuel, we need to make the best use out of the energy released by the chemical reaction. This fuel mix ended up being very white and semi-transluscent, traits which aren&amp;rsquo;t ideal for two reasons: white things reflect instead of absorbing, and non-opaque things tend to let light thru them. We need the grain to absorb as much heat from the combusting gases as possible, and we need that heat to remain at the outermost layer of the fuel. In order to achieve this, we want to make the grain opaque somehow, and we want the reacting gases to radiate as much heat as possible. Carbon Black, Lampblack, or Soot was what we chose. Adding just 1-5%wt of Carbon Black to the mix made the fuel completely opaque and it created a very incandescent exhaust as expected, but the kicker was that we got about 10% more thrust out of this simple change. Free performance glitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;combustion-chamber&#34;&gt;Combustion Chamber
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going from forward to aft, the major components of a typical hybrid combustion chamber are: Injector Carrier/Forward Closure, Casing, Thermal Liner, Nozzle, Nozzle Retainer. Designs may vary going from system to system but the basic components generally remain the same. While the concept of rocket propulsion remains relatively standard between solids, liquids, and hybrids, hybrids have a few particular quirks that drive the design of the combustion chamber in order to maximize performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a liquid engine, for example. Two propellants are injected into the chamber, mixed together and ignited. Straight forward enough. This involves careful timing and geometric design in order to guarantee that your propellants get to know each other as well as possible before they get the chance to burn. Inefficient mixing leads to loss of performance, so the art comes down to the injector design and chamber geometry (as well as other tricks involving preheating or preburning one or both of the propellants, not the focus of this discussion). On the other hand, you&amp;rsquo;ve got solids. Your propellants are mixed together homogeneously during manufacturing, meaning you have a mixture ratio and properties that are essentially set in stone. Major drawback is that potent fuels and oxidizers in close proximity to each other are a recipe for disaster. This is where hybrids come in and attempt to reach a goldilocks spot between these two. Conventionally, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a solid fuel and a liquid or gaseous oxidizer being injected. You still have the simplicity of solids and most of their form factor, but since your propellants are still separate from one another, you have the inherent safety of a liquid platform. The benefits truly end here, as they tend to inherit some of the worst performance issues of either counterpart. They&amp;rsquo;re hard to ignite, since as mentioned above you need to vaporize that fuel in order for it to ignite, which is rendered borderline impossible when your oxidizer is undergoing a phase transition right upstream wicking a lot of your igniter&amp;rsquo;s energy (we&amp;rsquo;ll get into this soon, I promise). It&amp;rsquo;s hard to ignite the whole grain face at once, mixing is a problem because fuel vapors are produced at the inner face of the grain white the oxidizer is injected flowing longitudinally,meaning a boundary layer forms where the two are supposed to be getting to know each other well. Diffusion is the primary mechanism driving mixing, and unfortunately without clever engineering it leads to horrible combustion performance and a ton of unburnt propellants being expelled without reacting. But this is where engineers thrive, with careful consideration, a lot of these issues can be mitigated to turn this into a somewhat tolerable platform for something like a sounding rocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting started at the forward end with the oxidizer. In Pegasus, the oxidizer of choice is Nitrous Oxide. You might know this as laughing gas, or whippets. It&amp;rsquo;s cheap, plentiful, and most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s part of the family of refrigerant gases. This last feature is a double edged sword, where it can be stored at a relatively low pressure as a liquid, it&amp;rsquo;s self-pressurizing and it&amp;rsquo;s got an awesome density at its ideal storage temperature, also it flashes into a gas the second that pressure drops below a threshold, which serves very well when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to get it to atomize and mix with the fuel in the chamber. However, the refrigerant side of things comes in and it will devour all the heat around it in order to support the phase transition, think turning a can of keyboard duster upside down. Additionally, when the fluid speeds up, pressure drops, which leads to two phase flow and cavitation, both of which are headahces in trying to design something to run at steady state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to take care of these issues, in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: This did not happen in this narrative order in real life. Truth is, you need the rest of the system to be able to iterate on fuels and hone everything the way portrayed above)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valve-control&#34;&gt;Valve Control
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oxidizer flow was controlled by a servo strapped to a ball valve. Simple enough for a team getting into valve control, robust enough not to introduce too much uncertainty into our design. Although we found out real quick what happens when you keep sending position information to an uncooled servo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Printed cage around valve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-campaign&#34;&gt;Testing Campaign
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Burn ban&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ground Support Issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Test
Second Test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;irec-2023&#34;&gt;IREC 2023
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Integration Nightmare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Nitrous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements-and-final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements and Final Thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article highlights primarily the work I was directly spearheading, but ultimately this is all the culmination of a team of equally talented people working towards a common goal. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my peers in the propulsion team for their help getting this from whiteboard drawings up into the air, as well as the people involved in every other supporting subsystem ranging from avionics to aerostuctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy some pictures from IREC 2023 and the later launch in Florida!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peggy pics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to Cope with Being a Film Lab Tech</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post How to Cope with Being a Film Lab Tech" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working at a film lab for the last couple of months, and the engineering degree immediately made itself useful by giving me the tools to keep some of these machines alive. Problems ranging from just corrosion within a sensor&amp;rsquo;s connector to open heart surgery on a board no longer made. For a glorified sous-vide tank, the Noritsu engineers put a lot of safeguards and smart engineering in place to keep these working as well as they have for as long as they have. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this article with the intention of logging whatever I find for whoever takes over for me, or whoever finds this website in similar despair as I have googled whenever something broke. There&amp;rsquo;s also the nice side effect of showing off the stuff between my ears to employers. Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1581&#34;
	height=&#34;1655&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines_hu_40e4bf388d6e5b95.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines_hu_6afb7710e738d341.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;V50 (larger), V30 (smaller)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;229px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the V50, relatively sophisticated MiniLab unit for C-41 Color Development. Short Leader style, which means you tape the film to a sheet of plastic with sprocket holes on it, and that&amp;rsquo;s what drags the film itself out of the can and into each step of the development process. The 50 in V50 stands for 50 rolls an hour, so not too shabby accounting for the fact a 36 exposure roll of film tends to be somewhere around 5 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to put the rest of the machine in context, let&amp;rsquo;s cover the development steps of Black and White and C-41 film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both, the film is coated with silver halide crystals. Exactly how they are spread on the film and what they do during and after the development process varies between B/W, C-41, and every other development process available, but the working principle remains the same. After being exposed to light, these crystals are raised to a higher energy level, leaving a latent image stored chemically on the film emulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2560&#34;
	height=&#34;784&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing_hu_c1aa083cf5197cde.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing_hu_f284969c6be4a63e.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Essential Steps of Development (Source:Wikipedia)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;326&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;783px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B/W:
-Developer: This step converts the latent image contained in the activated silver halide into metallic silver. This metallic silver only appears in the locations where light struck the emulsion. The stronger the light, the more concentrated the silver, the darker or &amp;ldquo;denser&amp;rdquo; the image is at this location, and the reverse applies as well. All of this to say that we now have a negative image of what was captured in the camera at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Fixer: After the developer, the image that matters to us is created. However, it&amp;rsquo;s still surrounded by the inactive silver halides still in the emulsion. No light, no developer action, no metallic silver. The fixer can dissolve the halides but not metallic silver, which allows us to selectively remove the unused stuff and keep our image negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy stuff, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing monochrome stuff essentially as long as we have been able to reliably understand organic chemistry. B/W film made a year ago and 80 years ago work the exact same, and excluding the effects of age, can be developed the exact same way. Color, however, is where modernity truly shines through. Kudos to all the chemists and engineers that allowed us to record the world around us in more than shadows and highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure.png&#34;
	width=&#34;960&#34;
	height=&#34;520&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure_hu_ffca95b32759b63b.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure_hu_fe242140875926.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Superia Emulsion Cross-Section (Source:Wikipedia)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;184&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;443px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C-41:
-Developer: Still does the same as B/W, with the caveat that now the dye couplers (part that creates the colors) are activated and create the dyes of each layer. Fun fact, you can cross-process any C-41 roll as B/W, you just ignore the color couplers for a monochrome image. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to salvage pictures from obsolete C-22 rolls from 60+ years ago. Hard drives fail, files go corrupt, but in a decently wide range of conditions, chemistry prevails. Cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Bleach: Due to the layout of a typical C-41 film emulsion, after development, you now have both a dye-based image, and the metallic silver image. Keeping both of these leads to super dense images with low saturation, and often it was used intentionally as a color grading effect in movies and TV in a method called &amp;ldquo;bleach bypass&amp;rdquo;. The bleach attacks this metallic image and converts it back to silver halides, which can now be removed by the fixer. It also helps reducing the density of the dyes in the film base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Fixer: Same as B/W. Fixer actually holds quite a decent amount of silver, so it&amp;rsquo;s very important to dispose of properly and feed it to silver reclaiming facilities. Not that any other chemical is great for carelessly dumping into the environment, but the fixer carries metals with it that are specially bad to introduce into an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Stabilizer: The dyes contained on each layer are technically not fixed in space, and age, environmental factors, and improper handling of the film can lead to them migrating between layers. The end effect is a reduction in the color reproduction quality, so stabilizers are used to &amp;ldquo;lock&amp;rdquo; the dyes out of escaping their layer. You can very well skip this step if you are just looking for a glorified Instagram filter, but in order to produce negatives that can withstand the test of time, stabilization is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to get into detail about the careful design of color emulsions, but so have another 500 trillion people on the internet, so I will unfortunately not elaborate here. Google it, watch Tech Connections about it, don&amp;rsquo;t use this case of brevity as an excuse to avoid learning about film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our machine feeds the leader card and the film it&amp;rsquo;s attached to into a very deep 18 Liter Color Developer (CD) tank at a speed that allows for each length of film to be in contact with the CD solution, while automatically adding a replenishment amount of fresh chemical to account for exhaustion per roll. All the chemicals involved in these reactions are disposable and need to be replenished accounting for the surface area that passes through. The film is continued to be carried in and out of the solutions automagically by careful mechanical design of roller transports like conveyors through a factory. The machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually know where this film is, but it vaguely knows when it started being fed and when the canister was cut off at the end, and it knows how fast everything is spinning and moving the film along. So it starts counting and can make an educated guess as to where it&amp;rsquo;d be and what chemicals would be exhausted at which times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, it passes through essentially a gentler air fryer before being released fully dry for it to be scanned and/or sleeved for preservation. Almost magical coming from my background of hanging up film from my shower curtain loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1466&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50_hu_8b0122298ca19550.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50_hu_aecb27f69d67701.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Noritsu QSF-V30&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;109&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;261px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected to mention much about the modified V30 that develops B/W, but it&amp;rsquo;s the same principles and same tech, just behaving differently to accomodate for the different chemistry. Both operate the same. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-recent-color-developer-working-tank-overheating&#34;&gt;Most Recent: Color Developer Working Tank Overheating
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;symptoms&#34;&gt;Symptoms:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermitent S-Sol Thermo Activated Error&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution reaches 43C before other safeguards kick in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially only happened during overnight sleep cycle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Initial Troubleshooting:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared thermocouple readings to thermometer in working tank and in side tank (will elaborate on tank layout in a second)
&amp;ndash; Temp Matches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drained tank, cleaned agitation and recirculation pumps
&amp;ndash; Minor to Negligible Improvement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context, we had just recovered from the below problem of the cutter jamming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I came back to the machine, I noticed that although the troubleshooting LEDs on the machine showed the control unit was not powering the heater relay, temperature continued to climb. Coming from the car background, tapping around with the rubber back of a screwdriver didn&amp;rsquo;t help. Turns out SSR stands for Solid State Relay, something I realized pretty late, embarassingly late. The awesome engineers at Noritsu had the foresight of including redundant relays on the board, or rather, populating relay footprints for heater circuits not used in this machine model. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the V100 or the V5Billion use these relays, but I&amp;rsquo;m lucky mine doesn&amp;rsquo;t because these exact P/Ns are looooooong discontinued. In my panic before realizing there were spares I did find a suitable drop-in replacement. Here&amp;rsquo;s the link in case you&amp;rsquo;re not so lucky to have a relay cache on your board.  I would like the record to show that I called it early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World&amp;rsquo;s oldest solder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1_hu_93685407cdf85bae.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1_hu_fbf845d356c5dfa3.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Board in Question&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2160&#34;
	height=&#34;2874&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2_hu_aabeb9fefb297485.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2_hu_91867f1fcb2743c8.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Mounted on the V50&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;75&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;180px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2160&#34;
	height=&#34;2518&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit_hu_c669376e8c07f439.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit_hu_1e1e222c1419b654.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Culprit&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;85&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;205px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2_hu_df908385250d6428.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2_hu_6b638e8e042fbeb5.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Where I found It&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah. Looking at the board closer would&amp;rsquo;ve saved quite a bit of time. If you noticed the missing pad, you try to babysit a board like this into releasing a component and tell me how it goes. It&amp;rsquo;s like they glued it on like a postage stamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cutter-jams&#34;&gt;Cutter Jams
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;symptoms-1&#34;&gt;Symptoms:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right Lane Struggled to Cut Canister at the End of the roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canisters stuck after cutting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutter Return Error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-troubleshooting-1&#34;&gt;Initial Troubleshooting
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/about-me/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/about-me/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/about-me/lathe.jpg" alt="Featured image of post About Me" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This website is meant to be a living document, with the intention of acting as a personal wiki for my previous, ongoing, and future projects. A digital garden of sorts. One of my 2025 New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions was to put together an updated portfolio showcasing my background for new acquaintances, as well as potential employers. Documentation is a skill every engineer should have, and I deeply believe in the open source mission, so I will be doing my best to explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on inside my head. &lt;b&gt;Beware: thoughts and ideas may be half finished. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogs like waxy.org, hackaday, and the countless personal sites I&amp;rsquo;ve come across from talented engineers and hobbyists inspired this website. I grew up doing my research and learning from many of these people, so I figured that I should document my projects and broadcast them into the hyperspace aether. The URL comes from the callouts performed during the Apollo missions. It means conditions are viable for the crew to perform a trans-lunar injection (TLI) burn, hence &amp;ldquo;Go for TLI&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a pseudonym I began using for my photography projects that sounded unique enough for a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to talk about the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on, so feel free to reach out! I&amp;rsquo;m more than willing to expand upon anything on this site, feedback is much appreciated. My socials are on that sidebar on the left, pick your poison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a potential employee, please reach out via e-mail at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:anegrette@protonmail.com&#34; &gt;anegrette@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-background&#34;&gt;My Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am an Aerospace Engineer with a background in gas dynamics and propulsion, primarily through collegiate sounding rocketry. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored much of everything that bringing an idea from a napkin drawing to a polished design, including short-run production. I participated in the &lt;strong&gt;International Rocket Engineering Competition&lt;/strong&gt; for a couple of years, primarily overseeing the development of the hybrid rocket motor for each participating rocket. Pictured is my favorite project, Pegasus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/about-me/pegasuslaunch.png&#34;
	width=&#34;367&#34;
	height=&#34;1400&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/about-me/pegasuslaunch_hu_fb9e6aab8f8258a6.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/about-me/pegasuslaunch_hu_9fa3d74126be148d.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pegasus during Flight&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;26&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;62px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My senior design project involved a &lt;strong&gt;Rotating Detonation Engine&lt;/strong&gt;, designed with the intention of contributing to the global understanding of RDEs, as well as creating an air breathing small-scale platform ready to be integrated with a flight vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My machining work experience encompasses 2, 3, and 4 axis CNC machining, as well as resin (DLP) additive manufacturing. Due to my time as a machinist I have developed an intuition for competent design with manufacturing and production in mind. In terms of Additive Manufacturing, I spearheaded the implementation of a Stratasys Origin One Photopolymerization Machine, including the creation of brand new procedures to maximize part repeatability, a critical part of the prototyping work I did for the UCF Machine Shop. I received training directly from Stratasys to maintain and repair the machine and its local print server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the academic and professional lens, I like to spend my free time browsing for obsolete tech on eBay, playing guitar and reading. I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching myself computer and electrical engineering, in part because I feel a Mech/Aero Engineer in the 21st century should be somewhat competent in the computers that support everything we build, and in part because I&amp;rsquo;d like to know how to repair the stuff I buy on eBay. One of my ongoing projects involves a Tang Nano 9k FPGA dev board as a platform for learning digital logic design and Verilog HDL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-site&#34;&gt;The Site
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do NOT have a web dev background, but I had enough brain to cobble together enough readme&amp;rsquo;s and stack overflow google searches to put this together. Built on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, using the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/CaiJimmy/hugo-theme-stack-starter&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hugo Stack Theme&lt;/a&gt;. Immense thanks to people who put their code on the internet for our combined benefit. FOSS rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, whether this attracts employers or not, I just wanted to compile all the work I&amp;rsquo;ve done into one cohesive document. I love this field, and much like a conventional garden is a product of love and care, this is my love note to engineering. Thank you for the visit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Photography</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/photography/scope.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Photography" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;equipment-background-and-other-thoughts&#34;&gt;Equipment, Background, and Other Thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started out with photography with a passed down Rebel T3. Not the latest or newest, but a perfectly capable sensor, well featured body, and it used the widely supported EF-S Canon mount. It allowed me to get my feet wet with the field, and besides, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to believe that having the newest, most expensive tool instantly makes you better at anything (to an extent). This applies to photography as well. Beyond quality of life features, a camera is a dark box with light input on one end and a light sensitive element on the other. In terms of image quality, improvements to digital sensors quickly became asymptotic for a casual photographer like me, so I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on learning about composition, color correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canondslr.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canondslr_hu_c02b7fc6b0af4a92.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/canondslr_hu_c631f2c39f8ef3ed.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Rebel T3 (Source: Canon USA)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time after, I came across a Rebel X SLR for extremely cheap. Most of the used film camera market orbits around a handful of critically acclaimed camera makes and models, and many well featured and advanced cameras tend to lurk in their shade. This specific camera appealed to the exact same market as the other Rebel, sporting an equally well balanced featureset catering to beginners. My favorite part about film is that the technology was essentially perfected by the end of the film era, so a majority of film cameras in the late 90s and early 00s share the exact same technology as DSLRs even to this day. Look at the very first DSLRs to hit the market; they are almost carbon copies of the final SLR models. My Rebel X is compatible with the exact same autofocus and metering system as my much newer DSLR, so it was as smooth of a transition into film as I could&amp;rsquo;ve wished for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canonslr.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;520&#34;
	height=&#34;414&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canonslr_hu_b9a2f803acf96968.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/canonslr_hu_9005d7a4d89a51be.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Rebel X (Source: Canon USA)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;301px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through my fair share of rolls, I invested into a Pentax KX to learn photography down to a subconscious understanding of creative metering, composing, and to break the habit of treating the camera as a point and shoot. I began working at the film lab, which exposed me to what my peers felt and thought about the analog medium. Being forced to focus, think about what my aperture and shutter speed settings are doing in terms of the frame I am about to campture makes the images much more meaningful and connected to me as a photographer. Ansel Adams did not have the technology that we have within the latest Canon or Nikon flagships, yet he managed to create images so powerful as to encourage the appreciation of the beauty that spans the American continent, and the creation of the National Parks throughout the US. We live in an era where cameras are perpetually within reach in our pockets, yet it&amp;rsquo;s the most disconnected from photography I&amp;rsquo;ve felt. Pictures I take on my phone quickly fade into the depths of my camera roll, while the pictures I have taken on film all remain fresh in my psyche as the day I composed the shot through the viewfinder. The cherry on top is that the actual photons my camera saw at that instant are captured chemically to endure the years. Hard drives fail, servers and services shut down, yet grandpa&amp;rsquo;s Kodachrome slides from the 70s have withstood the test of time and will continue to do so. As technology advances, these masters have allowed us to reproduce mind bending quality from movies and TV recordings purely because they were stored chemically on film as opposed to magnetic tape or whatever other alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pentax.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1067&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pentax_hu_9f00f3aaa2066fa1.webp 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/pentax_hu_472fa4d104372817.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pentax KX (Source: 35MMC)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working as a developer with my background in engineering has made me appreciate the work of the thousands of people throughout centuries working to capture their lives. This ramble is a thinly veiled open love letter to the chemists, engineers, and designers at Kodak, Fujifilm, and the thousands of other companies that brought the ability to create snapshots of special moments to the masses. It moves me deeply that more and more people share this sentiment and are powering a film resurgence. I understand the purpose and the niche for digital photography, but the same way that one can choose to write something on paper versus typing it into a Word document, I believe film photography has an equal right to exist in the Internet era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of film photography, I get a little more in depth about the chemistry and construction of photographic film over in my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/&#34; &gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about my time as a film tech and the troubleshooting/repairing of some of our machines. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever sent out a roll to be developed and scanned, it&amp;rsquo;s a good behind-the-scenes view of why there&amp;rsquo;s delays and errors every once in a while. These are machines on life support with limited availability of replacement parts and plenty of lost knowledge from generations of engineers that retired at the beginning of the millenium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, see some of my favorites below. Thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-recent-shots&#34;&gt;My Favorite Recent Shots
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/scope.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;799&#34;
	height=&#34;530&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/scope_hu_a7894beeb31c1625.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/scope_hu_9696659eb8d648f0.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My Workstation&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;361px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/roots.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;679&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/roots_hu_2fb6918a913d8fcd.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/roots_hu_b71b3707cbf503b7.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Roots&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;66&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;159px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pigeons.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;679&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pigeons_hu_6d2af6430398ceda.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/pigeons_hu_3792bc2a7e864085.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pigeons (a film point and shoot took this!)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;361px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>CT Inverse Radon Implementation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/computed-tomography/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/computed-tomography/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rotating Detonation Engines (RDEs) are a relatively novel form of rocket propulsion that takes advantage of pressure-gain combustion. Conventional rocket engines use constant-pressure combustion cycles. RDEs theoretically produce better performance by taking better advantage of the energy stored chemically in the propellants. There is a fine line between detonating in the way that yields the performance advantage, and detonating in the way that destroys the engine. Due to the speeds involved in the process, these engines have only recently began gaining traction now that computers and sensors allow for the extremely fast sampling rates necessary for reliable data output. Their compact size allows for storable propellants to be used more effectively in missile and defense applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals of this project at the beginning were beyond creating a working air breathing lab scale engine, to lay the foundation for further research to be done at UCF. This involved creating a test stand equipped with a capable and robust data acquisition system and control system. With the tight budget for a project of this ambition we had to get creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ignition&#34;&gt;Ignition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lighting an RDE involves precise timing and a strong enough relese of energy to induce a detonation mode within the engine. A fast burst (in tens of micro seconds) with not a lot of energy is more likely to induce a detonation compared to a longer burst with a ton more energy. Typically predets are used where an explosive mixture of gases are lit on one end of a long tube and over that length of tube the energy release is structured in such a way a shock is developed by the time the combusting gases exit. Due to the mechanism of operation, these have careful geometry that is hard to package into a system with compact and flight in mind. This is where my approach comes in, conventional torch. If the annulus can act as the constriction that focuses the energy towards a shock, the igniter can be more compact and allow for smaller designs for flight vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;humbled-by-testing&#34;&gt;Humbled by Testing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-design-showcase&#34;&gt;Senior Design Showcase
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future Plans
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;scitech&#34;&gt;SciTech
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts-and-acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts and Acknowledgements
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taha Dr. Burke, Teammates and UCF&amp;rsquo;s Senior Design Support System&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>1. Theme Installation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/installation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/installation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Create a new hugo website or open your existing hugo site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;add-the-theme-to-your-hugo-site&#34;&gt;Add the theme to your hugo site
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use as a git submodule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme.git themes/digitalgarden
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone the repository (one-off, updating the theme may be harder later):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme.git themes/digitalgarden
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;package-lock.json&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tailwind.config.js&lt;/code&gt; files from the theme/digitalgarden folder to the root folder of your the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; to install required packages for theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm i -g postcss-cli&lt;/code&gt; to use PostCSS with Hugo build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set &lt;code&gt;theme = &#39;digitalgarden&#39;&lt;/code&gt; in config.toml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm run dev&lt;/code&gt; to start your local server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When deploying to services like Netlify or Vercel, use the following command for building your site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;npm i -g postcss-cli &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; npm run build
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/structure&#34; &gt;Understanding the theme structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>2. Structure</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/structure/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/structure/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Understand the structure of the theme&amp;rsquo;s setup to create content for your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;themes-content-structure&#34;&gt;Theme&amp;rsquo;s content structure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;11
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;12
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;13
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mysql&#34; data-lang=&#34;mysql&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;                 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Hosts all Markdown content
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;articles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Contains the list of markdown files for notes/posts
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;portfolio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;           &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# List of portfolio projects or case studies
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Test files (alternatively `spec` or `tests`)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;          &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Data used for rendering the list in Stack page
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that articles, portfolio and also stack pages require you to create &lt;code&gt;_index.md&lt;/code&gt; inside of it. Refer the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme/tree/main/exampleSite&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;exampleSite&lt;/a&gt; in theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these sections are optional and you can decide not to utilize those layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/primary-menu&#34; &gt;Configure Primary Menu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>3. Primary Menu</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/primary-menu/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/primary-menu/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sidebar of the theme uses the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; menu. Add all the items for your sidebar navigation in this menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;// config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;11
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;12
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;13
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Home&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Content&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Articles&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/articles&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;  Title of the menu item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt;  Path to navigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;  Used to decide the order of menu items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;params.header&lt;/code&gt;  Display menu item as header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the link points to an external website, the external icon is already displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using JSON or YAML formats? Check out the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/menus/#simple&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;menu&lt;/a&gt; documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/social-menu&#34; &gt;Configure Social Menu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>4. Social Menu</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/social-menu/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/social-menu/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The social menu can be used to configure all the social icons in the sidebar. Add links to your social media in the website config to show the icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Twitter&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;https://twitter.com&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; of the social menu needs to be unique and should be one of the supported values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supported values for the social menu item name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dribbble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codepen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/newsletter&#34; &gt;Configure newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>5. Newsletter</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/newsletter/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/newsletter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The theme supports a subscription to multiple newsletter providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buttondown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Substack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buttondown&#34;&gt;Buttondown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Params.newsletter.provider] = &amp;ldquo;buttondown&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy the &lt;code&gt;action&lt;/code&gt; url from your buttondown admin dashboard and add it to &lt;strong&gt;[Params.newsletter.path]&lt;/strong&gt; in config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.buttondown.email/img/9.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Buttondown share form URL&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;substack&#34;&gt;Substack
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Params.newsletter.provider] = &amp;ldquo;substack&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up substack is the easiest. Just add your substack newsletter URL (applicable for custom domains also) to &lt;strong&gt;[Params.newsletter.path]&lt;/strong&gt; in config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that since substack doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a native API for subscription. The theme uses the api from substackapi.com which is in no way associated to Substack itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revue&#34;&gt;Revue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add your revue &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; URL to &lt;code&gt;Params.newsletter.path&lt;/code&gt; in your config.toml. Once done, the newsletter widget will start showing up in website&amp;rsquo;s sidebar, allowing your visitors to subscribe to your newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-find-your-revue-url-to-use&#34;&gt;How to find your Revue URL to use
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Login to your Revue account and go to to &lt;code&gt;Account Settings&lt;/code&gt;, then the &lt;code&gt;Integrations&lt;/code&gt; tab. Scroll to the bottom, and click on &lt;code&gt;Learn more&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Signup forms&lt;/strong&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://downloads.intercomcdn.com/i/o/304891471/587879182e5d9d19aff97d2f/Screenshot&amp;#43;2021-02-26&amp;#43;at&amp;#43;9.10.32&amp;#43;AM.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Revue signup forms&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next page, you can find the add_subscriber URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme/blob/main/images/revue-signup-form-url.png?raw=true&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Revue URL&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy it and use in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/google-analytics&#34; &gt;Add Google analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>6. Google Analytics</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/google-analytics/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/google-analytics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital garden theme utilizes the Hugo&amp;rsquo;s [internal template](internal templates) for Google analytics and so both Google analytics v3 and GA v4 (gtag) are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add your &lt;strong&gt;UA-PROPERTY_ID&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;G-MEASUREMENT_ID&lt;/strong&gt; to config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-analytics-v3-analyticsjs&#34;&gt;Google Analytics v3 (analytics.js)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;googleAnalytics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;UA-PROPERTY_ID&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-analytics-v4-gtagjs&#34;&gt;Google Analytics v4 (gtag.js)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;googleAnalytics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;G-MEASUREMENT_ID&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/metatags&#34; &gt;Configure Metatags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>7. Metatags</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/metatags/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/metatags/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Metatags are used to provide additional information about the page, usually used by search engines and social media websites / apps. It allows to customize your page&amp;rsquo;s title, description, preview image and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-default-tags&#34;&gt;Configure default tags
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;// config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Personal Digital Garden&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;My Digital Garden on the Internet&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/digital-garden-logo.png&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting the above values will be used as default for all pages unless its overridden in a specific page&amp;rsquo;s markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;customize-specific-pages-tags&#34;&gt;Customize specific page&amp;rsquo;s tags
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the markdown file of the page for which you need to customize the tags and set the following properties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;// custom-page.md&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Custom Page&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;My Custom page in the Digital Garden&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/custom-page.png&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These values will be used for open graph tags and twitter cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34;&gt;
If you like this theme, support by sharing it with friends on Twitter  &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Digital%20Garden%20theme%20for%20Hugo%0Ahttps%3A//github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;inline&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter URL&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/url?style=social&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fapvarun%2Fdigital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design1/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Croissant orange croissant dolor orange croissant. Lollipop biscuit donut vanilla sweet croissant. Apple donut candy tiramisu cream jelly. Croissant sweet cookie vanilla tiramisu dolor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange. Candy sweet cookie sweet donut marzipan. Vanilla cookie sprinkles pastry orange cookie. Marzipan donut ipsum sugar biscuit vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy cookie muffin pastry lollipop vanilla. Apple orange tiramisu jelly ipsum sugar. Candy cake orange ipsum orange muffin. Sugar pastry orange cream orange pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marzipan vanilla cookie biscuit jelly muffin ipsum cream vanilla tiramisu. Marzipan vanilla sweet tiramisu pastry cake jelly jelly pastry cake. Cookie sweet donut candy pastry apple dolor orange lollipop biscuit. Muffin cream ipsum ipsum sprinkles sugar tiramisu pastry sweet tiramisu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Cream sugar apple donut apple croissant</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design2/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tiramisu sprinkles marzipan lollipop marzipan dolor. Jelly candy marzipan vanilla candy ipsum. Sugar croissant lollipop vanilla cream marzipan. Sprinkles croissant cream dolor jelly marzipan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange. Candy sweet cookie sweet donut marzipan. Vanilla cookie sprinkles pastry orange cookie. Marzipan donut ipsum sugar biscuit vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy cookie muffin pastry lollipop vanilla. Apple orange tiramisu jelly ipsum sugar. Candy cake orange ipsum orange muffin. Sugar pastry orange cream orange pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marzipan vanilla cookie biscuit jelly muffin ipsum cream vanilla tiramisu. Marzipan vanilla sweet tiramisu pastry cake jelly jelly pastry cake. Cookie sweet donut candy pastry apple dolor orange lollipop biscuit. Muffin cream ipsum ipsum sprinkles sugar tiramisu pastry sweet tiramisu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Apple cream vanilla apple marzipan muffin</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design3/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design3/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tiramisu sprinkles marzipan lollipop marzipan dolor. Jelly candy marzipan vanilla candy ipsum. Sugar croissant lollipop vanilla cream marzipan. Sprinkles croissant cream dolor jelly marzipan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange. Candy sweet cookie sweet donut marzipan. Vanilla cookie sprinkles pastry orange cookie. Marzipan donut ipsum sugar biscuit vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy cookie muffin pastry lollipop vanilla. Apple orange tiramisu jelly ipsum sugar. Candy cake orange ipsum orange muffin. Sugar pastry orange cream orange pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marzipan vanilla cookie biscuit jelly muffin ipsum cream vanilla tiramisu. Marzipan vanilla sweet tiramisu pastry cake jelly jelly pastry cake. Cookie sweet donut candy pastry apple dolor orange lollipop biscuit. Muffin cream ipsum ipsum sprinkles sugar tiramisu pastry sweet tiramisu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Links</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/links/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/links/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To use this feature, add &lt;code&gt;links&lt;/code&gt; section to frontmatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page&amp;rsquo;s frontmatter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;GitHub is the world&amp;#39;s largest software development platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;https://github.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/logos_page/GitHub-Mark.png&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;TypeScript is a typed superset of JavaScript that compiles to plain JavaScript.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;https://www.typescriptlang.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;ts-logo-128.jpg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;image&lt;/code&gt; field accepts both local and external images.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
