<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Arturo Negrette</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Arturo Negrette</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Chronicles from a Film Lab Tech</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Chronicles from a Film Lab Tech" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working at a film lab for the last couple of months, and the engineering degree immediately made itself useful by giving me the tools to keep some of these machines alive. Problems ranging from just corrosion within a sensor&amp;rsquo;s connector to open heart surgery on a board no longer made. For a glorified sous-vide tank, the Noritsu engineers put a lot of safeguards and smart engineering in place to keep these working as well as they have for as long as they have. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this article with the intention of logging whatever I find for whoever takes over for me, or whoever finds this website in similar despair as I have googled whenever something broke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1581&#34;
	height=&#34;1655&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines_hu_40e4bf388d6e5b95.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines_hu_6afb7710e738d341.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;V50 (larger), V30 (smaller)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;229px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the V50, relatively sophisticated MiniLab unit for C-41 Color Development. Short Leader style, which means you tape the film to a sheet of plastic with sprocket holes on it, and that&amp;rsquo;s what drags the film itself out of the can and into each step of the development process. The 50 in V50 stands for 50 rolls an hour, so not too shabby accounting for the fact a 36 exposure roll of film tends to be somewhere around 5 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to put the rest of the machine in context, let&amp;rsquo;s cover the development steps of Black and White and C-41 film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both, the film is coated with silver halide crystals. Exactly how they are spread on the film and what they do during and after the development process varies between B/W, C-41, and every other development process available, but the working principle remains the same. After being exposed to light, these crystals are raised to a higher energy level, leaving a latent image stored chemically on the film emulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2560&#34;
	height=&#34;784&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing_hu_c1aa083cf5197cde.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing_hu_f284969c6be4a63e.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Essential Steps of Development (Source:Wikipedia)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;326&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;783px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B/W&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt;: This step converts the latent image contained in the activated silver halide into metallic silver. This metallic silver only appears in the locations where light struck the emulsion. The stronger the light, the more concentrated the silver, the darker or &#34;denser&#34; the image is at this location, and the reverse applies as well. All of this to say that we now have a negative image of what was captured in the camera at that moment. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixer&lt;/strong&gt;: After the developer, the image that matters to us is created. However, it&#39;s still surrounded by the inactive silver halides still in the emulsion. No light, no developer action, no metallic silver. The fixer can dissolve the halides but not metallic silver, which allows us to selectively remove the unused stuff and keep our image negative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy stuff, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing monochrome stuff essentially as long as we have been able to understand organic chemistry. B/W film made a year ago and 80 years ago work the exact same, and excluding the effects of age, can be developed the exact same way. Color, however, is where modernity truly shines through. Kudos to all the chemists and engineers that allowed us to record the world around us in more than shadows and highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure.png&#34;
	width=&#34;960&#34;
	height=&#34;520&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure_hu_ffca95b32759b63b.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure_hu_fe242140875926.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Superia Emulsion Cross-Section (Source:Wikipedia)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;184&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;443px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C-41&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt;: Still does the same as B/W, with the caveat that now the dye couplers (part that creates the colors) are activated and create the dyes of each layer. Fun fact, you can cross-process any C-41 roll as B/W, you just ignore the color couplers for a monochrome image. I&#39;ve managed to salvage pictures from obsolete C-22 rolls from 60+ years ago. Hard drives fail, files go corrupt, but in a decently wide range of conditions, chemistry prevails. Cool stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bleach&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to the layout of a typical C-41 film emulsion, after development, you now have both a dye-based image, and the metallic silver image. Keeping both of these leads to super dense images with low saturation, and often it was used intentionally as a color grading effect in movies and TV in a method called &#34;bleach bypass&#34;. The bleach attacks this metallic image and converts it back to silver halides, which can now be removed by the fixer. It also helps reducing the density of the dyes in the film base.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixer&lt;/strong&gt;: Same as B/W. Fixer actually holds quite a decent amount of silver, so it&#39;s very important to dispose of properly and feed it to silver reclaiming facilities. Not that any other chemical is great for carelessly dumping into the environment, but the fixer carries metals with it that are specially bad to introduce into an ecosystem. 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stabilizer&lt;/strong&gt;: The dyes contained on each layer are technically not fixed in space, and age, environmental factors, and improper handling of the film can lead to them migrating between layers. The end effect is a reduction in the color reproduction quality, so stabilizers are used to &#34;lock&#34; the dyes out of escaping their layer. You can very well skip this step if you are just looking for a glorified Instagram filter, but in order to produce negatives that can withstand the test of time, stabilization is crucial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to get into detail about the careful design of color emulsions, but so have another 500 trillion people on the internet, so I will unfortunately not elaborate here. Google it, watch Tech Connections about it, don&amp;rsquo;t use this case of brevity as an excuse to avoid learning about film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our machine feeds the leader card and the film it&amp;rsquo;s attached to into a very deep 18 Liter Color Developer (CD) tank at a speed that allows for each length of film to be in contact with the CD solution, while automatically adding a replenishment amount of fresh chemical to account for exhaustion per roll. All the chemicals involved in these reactions are disposable and need to be replenished accounting for the surface area that passes through. The film is continued to be carried in and out of the solutions automagically by careful mechanical design of roller transports like conveyors through a factory. The machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually know where this film is, but it vaguely knows when it started being fed and when the canister was cut off at the end, and it knows how fast everything is spinning and moving the film along. So it starts counting and can make an educated guess as to where it&amp;rsquo;d be and what chemicals would be exhausted at which times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, it passes through essentially a gentler air fryer before being released fully dry for it to be scanned and/or sleeved for preservation. Almost magical coming from my background of hanging up film from my shower curtain loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1466&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50_hu_8b0122298ca19550.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50_hu_aecb27f69d67701.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Noritsu QSF-V30&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;109&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;261px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected to mention much about the modified V30 that develops B/W, but it&amp;rsquo;s the same principles and same tech, just behaving differently to accomodate for the different chemistry. Both operate the same. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;repair-log&#34;&gt;Repair Log
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;most-recent-bw-intermittent-bootlooping&#34;&gt;Most Recent: B/W Intermittent &amp;ldquo;Bootlooping&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;symptoms&#34;&gt;Symptoms
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine goes into a cycle of booting and self-testing, encountering some error and powering down, then repeating the cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially only happened at the end of a roll, right after cutting the canister off. One reboot cycle and it would continue as normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progressed to continously turning off and on again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;troubleshooting--false-solution&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting + False Solution
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;My initial assumption was an intermittent short in a system related to the springloaded blades that cut the end of the film from the canister. It&amp;rsquo;s a guillotine that&amp;rsquo;s tensioned until it hits a detente to hold the spring securely. When the can is pulled closer as the roll runs out, it hits a paddle that trips the spring catch and the blade flies into the film, cutting it off. The spring is loaded via a motor on a cam, so I started checking that the motor actuated freely, which it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of each day, a start check is completed where a leader card is fed through the machine with no film attached to it in order to confirm that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with the extensive tree of gears and rollers that transports everything from beginning to end. I noticed that during this test the problem still occured, even though the motor was not involved and the cutter was not triggered. It ruled out anything wrong with that subsystem, giving me a dead end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting the service manual pointed me to a logic issue with the front panel control board, where I started poking around until I found out through a tech at one of the other labs that something similar happened when the front panel button connection was corroded. Upon cleaning and reseating the cable the problem was fixed. Straight forward enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/ribbonlocation.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3024&#34;
	height=&#34;3158&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/ribbonlocation_hu_d0e60931674f75bf.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/ribbonlocation_hu_6e43ca0d786523dd.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Ribbon Cable in Question&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;229px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months passed and the problem returned, where we&amp;rsquo;d clean the cable and reseat it, helping for a couple weeks until the issue appeared again. Every cleaning would return everything to normal but the time until the problem reappeared was slowly getting shorter until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, it had been several months of increasingly more regular cycling on the ribbon cable. The usual cleaning and reseating got to a point where it did not solve the issue at all, the machine could not be used at all. When I took it apart and inspected the ribbon cable under a loupe I found that the contact material had fully worn through, and I presume it wasn&amp;rsquo;t making contact at all. I unfortunately did not take a picture of the damage before the first fix, but looking at the picture below, the untouched side shows the gist of it. The contacts on the board wore a hole through the pads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version 1&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were pretty backed up in terms of black and white orders, so I needed to get the machine to stop cycling and begin processing film. I had the idea of using aluminum tape from one of the film stocks we sell. They make their DX codes by sticking some aluminum tape and putting a label over it in order to make the pattern of conductive/non-conductive squares. Pretty neat. Turned out pretty sloppy but it got the job done to catch up with orders. Let&amp;rsquo;s call this one Version 1.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version1-0.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1385&#34;
	height=&#34;1433&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version1-0_hu_e9fb59854451dd7f.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version1-0_hu_8c3345c0d3d1f219.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Version 1.0 of the fix&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;96&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;231px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version1-1.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2749&#34;
	height=&#34;2530&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version1-1_hu_2f2b8d2a77718b91.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version1-1_hu_30cb96148bbaee77.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Version 1.1 of the fix&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;108&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;260px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, some of the buttons were intermitently working, so I knew we couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep this for the long term. We had ordered some X-Acto knives so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d redo the patchwork with sharper blades whenever those came in. Version 1.1 turned out more aesthetically pleasing but actually gave its own set of issues. For example, the set of buttons that were acting up with 1.0 returned to life, but a different set did not work at all and in fact ended up sticking and led the machine to behave erratically. This told me that I was now shorting adjacent pads to one another or to ground around the connector body. At this point I realized the tape we use for taping the film to the leader cards was pretty perfect as a low-temp Kapton tape alternative and the idea for V2 was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version 2&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For V2 I had two major conclusions driving how I went about this next repair. First, I needed to shield everything besides the actual contact point in order to prevent any more shorting. I was very lucky I didn&amp;rsquo;t fry anything that last time. I also needed to have better contact between the original flex PCB traces and the aluminum tape, so I needed to flip the aluminum tape in order to keep the glue from acting as an insulator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version2-0.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2195&#34;
	height=&#34;2219&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version2-0_hu_aacccc39f744ffb6.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/version2-0_hu_19372b6725866f4b.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Version 2.0 of the fix&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;98&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;237px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By stenciling the actual location of the worn contacts onto some tape, I was able to shield everything else and it made the size, shape and location of my aluminum tape squares less critical. I was also able to stick them onto the bottom of the tape and rinse off the adhesive from it with some alcohol. It took me the longest out of all the solutions I came up with but at this point it&amp;rsquo;s the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to a permanent fix short of replacing the board altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;color-developer-working-tank-overheating&#34;&gt;Color Developer Working Tank Overheating
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;symptoms-1&#34;&gt;Symptoms
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermitent S-Sol Thermo Activated Error&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution reaches 43C before other safeguards kick in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially only happened during overnight sleep cycle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;initial-troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Initial Troubleshooting
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared thermocouple readings to thermometer in working tank and in side tank (will elaborate on tank layout in a second)
&amp;ndash; Temp Matches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drained tank, cleaned agitation and recirculation pumps
&amp;ndash; Minor to Negligible Improvement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context, we had just recovered from the below problem of the cutter jamming, so at this point we had been chasing problems around for around a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preventative maintenance is crucial for keeping old hardware like this up and running. Much like one of my old bosses used to say: &amp;ldquo;Schedule the maintenance or the machine will schedule it for you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to the problem, at first the heater would behave but over time it started getting stuck powered on during normal operation and not just during the overnight sleep mode. When we confirmed that the machine was reading the correct temperature for the tank, it indicated to me that a relay was getting stuck closed intermittently. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s a team project and the rest of the team wanted to confirm nothing else was out of the ordinary before ruling in favor of swapping the relay. I didn&amp;rsquo;t work for a couple days so the rest of the team limped the machine through and only took 3 day turnaround orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a quick brush through the service manual and found that the stabilizer control system and the one for the tank giving us problems was the exact same, so I swapped its thermocouple and heater, making the machine believe that the stabilizer was the color dev tank and viceversa. The heater loops all were controlled via components labeled SSR1 through 7, all on the power board at the bottom of the machine. Unsurprisingly, the stabilizer was now overheating instead. Luckily, we could run the stabilizer at room temperature so disabling the color developer heater could let us run the machine and catch up with orders before a repair needs to be done. I reset the thermostat for the stabilizer to what it needed to be for color developer (remember that color dev is now stabilizer from the point of view of the machine and viceversa), and then set the color developer temperature to zero so it would not attempt to power anything on that circuit. The machine slowly got up to temperature and remained there as it was now able to turn off the color developer heater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1_hu_93685407cdf85bae.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1_hu_fbf845d356c5dfa3.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Power Board&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2160&#34;
	height=&#34;2874&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2_hu_aabeb9fefb297485.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2_hu_91867f1fcb2743c8.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Mounted on the V50&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;75&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;180px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we caught up with orders for the most part, so I carried on with trying to fix the root cause. When I came back to the machine, I noticed that although the troubleshooting LEDs on the power board showed the control unit was not powering the heater relay, temperature continued to climb. From my car background I had the intuition to begin tapping around every black relay-looking box with the rubber back of a screwdriver. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out SSR stands for Solid State Relay, something I realized pretty late, embarassingly late. SSRs tend to fail closed as they&amp;rsquo;re semiconductor devices, and it confirmed and explained my initial assumption of a stuck relay. The awesome engineers at Noritsu had the foresight of including redundant relays on the board, or rather, populating relay footprints for heater circuits not used in this machine model. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the V100 or the V5Billion use these relays, but I&amp;rsquo;m lucky mine doesn&amp;rsquo;t because these exact P/Ns are looooooong discontinued. In my panic before realizing there were spares I did find a suitable drop-in replacement. I crossreferenced the info on the part itself, the pin pitch from the board and the specs from the service manual. Part number is D2W203F-11 and below are some links to find a replacement in case you&amp;rsquo;re not so lucky to have extras:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.digikey.com/en/products/detail/sensata-crydom/D2W203F-11/139583&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Digikey&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.mouser.com/ProductDetail/Crydom/D2W203F-11?qs=mNyg5qXQ%2FscFP3eDV%2F5phw%3D%3D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mouser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closely inspecting the board would&amp;rsquo;ve saved a bit of time, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to get out of the machine and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to take it out unless absolutely necessary. These things are a couple grand each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2160&#34;
	height=&#34;2518&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit_hu_c669376e8c07f439.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit_hu_1e1e222c1419b654.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Culprit&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;85&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;205px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/RelayMounted.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/RelayMounted_hu_ddab5f295bb322a8.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/RelayMounted_hu_ff07ce67ef61c572.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Where I found It&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A candidate for the world&amp;rsquo;s oldest solder was holding the relay in place, so a ton of flux, time and patience were needed to get it out and replaced with the extra. The pad was fried to begin with, and I presume that solder started cracking and creating a high resistance connection. The thermal cycling probably also weakened the joint and created a feedback loop culminating where we are now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad1.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad1_hu_bb6f80e6c86bc88b.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad1_hu_fd0237a6248a45f2.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Bottom of PCB&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2_hu_df908385250d6428.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2_hu_6b638e8e042fbeb5.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Space left by relay&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After it was all said and done, I gave the board a good dusting and a rinse with isopropyl alcohol to wash of the flux all over the board and give it some TLC. Once installed, the heater problem was solved and it&amp;rsquo;s still powering through orders to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cutter-jams&#34;&gt;Cutter Jams
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;symptoms-2&#34;&gt;Symptoms
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right Lane Struggled to Cut Canister at the End of the roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canisters stuck after cutting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutter Return Error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;initial-troubleshooting-1&#34;&gt;Initial Troubleshooting
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-chemistry-experiments&#34;&gt;Film Chemistry Experiments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;c-41-reversal&#34;&gt;C-41 Reversal
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;black-and-white-reversal&#34;&gt;Black and White Reversal
&lt;/h3&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Teletypewriter Retrofit</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/teletype/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/teletype/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/teletype/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Teletypewriter Retrofit" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a Smith Corona SL600 off eBay for $3 + shipping, the seller said it had an unfixable error that prevented it from starting up and only showed a rapid blinking light on the CapsLock indicator. I love taking gambles at anything on eBay with a clueless seller so I bought it. When it came in, I cleaned it, plugged it in and saw the same error as the seller. However, I had bought an extra set of ribbon cartridges and the one that came with the machine looked off to me, so I swapped it. To my surprise the very well designed typewriter sprung to life with the correct ribbon installed. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it to type letters and journaling but I&amp;rsquo;m retiring it in favor of a model with a better keyboard. As you&amp;rsquo;ll see below from my teardown, the 80s were a period of cost reduction and optimization, sometimes at the detriment of user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Intercepting keystrokes between the keyboard and the rest of the typewriter in order to control/hear what&#39;s being typed
- Developing a serial interface for the typewriter to act as a Linux terminal, much like early terminals of the 50s and 60s.
- Acting as a packet radio transceiver, putting the tele in teletypewriter
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-exploration&#34;&gt;Preliminary Exploration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took the typewriter apart to clean it and gaze at its insides. To my surprise, it&amp;rsquo;s probably the best model to modify for this project. As far as I can tell, logic listens out for which circuits are being closed as the operator types, and signals to type the corresponding letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking it apart further revealed that the keyboard is composed of a film PCB similar to modern membrane keyboards, where the keys press down a tree of stamped sheet metal levers that close exposed pads on the film surface via carbon-coated plungers. Essentially an ancestor of modern membrane keyboards, except that the PCB is optimized to be a ribbon across the center of the keyboard. My educated guess for this is the early restrictions on film PCBs would drive costs much higher if they had a PCB matching the footprint of the keyboard itself. Much cheaper to have the levers do the heavy lifting of connecting the outer keys to the center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-work&#34;&gt;Current Work
&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/about-me/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/about-me/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/about-me/lathe.jpg" alt="Featured image of post About Me" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This website is meant to be a living document, with the intention of acting as a personal wiki for my previous, ongoing, and future projects. A digital garden of sorts. One of my 2025 New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions was to put together an updated portfolio showcasing my background for new acquaintances, as well as potential employers. Documentation is a skill every engineer should have, and I deeply believe in the open source mission, so I will be doing my best to explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on inside my head. &lt;b&gt;Beware: thoughts and ideas may be half finished. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogs like waxy.org, hackaday, and the countless personal sites I&amp;rsquo;ve come across from talented engineers and hobbyists inspired this website. I grew up doing my research and learning from many of these people, so I figured that I should document my projects and broadcast them into the hyperspace aether. The URL comes from the callouts performed during the Apollo missions. It means conditions are viable for the crew to perform a trans-lunar injection (TLI) burn, hence &amp;ldquo;Go for TLI&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a pseudonym I began using for my photography projects that sounded unique enough for a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to talk about the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on, so feel free to reach out! I&amp;rsquo;m more than willing to expand upon anything on this site, feedback is much appreciated. My socials are on that sidebar on the left, pick your poison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a potential employee, please reach out via e-mail at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:anegrette@protonmail.com&#34; &gt;anegrette@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-background&#34;&gt;My Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am an Aerospace Engineer with a background in gas dynamics and propulsion, primarily through collegiate sounding rocketry. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored much of everything that bringing an idea from a napkin drawing to a polished design, including short-run production. I participated in the &lt;strong&gt;International Rocket Engineering Competition&lt;/strong&gt; for a couple of years, primarily overseeing the development of the hybrid rocket motor for each participating rocket. Pictured is my favorite project, Pegasus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/about-me/pegasuslaunch.png&#34;
	width=&#34;367&#34;
	height=&#34;1400&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/about-me/pegasuslaunch_hu_fb9e6aab8f8258a6.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/about-me/pegasuslaunch_hu_9fa3d74126be148d.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pegasus during Flight&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;26&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;62px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My senior design project involved a &lt;strong&gt;Rotating Detonation Engine&lt;/strong&gt;, designed with the intention of contributing to the global understanding of RDEs, as well as creating an air breathing small-scale platform ready to be integrated with a flight vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My machining work experience encompasses 2, 3, and 4 axis CNC machining, as well as resin (DLP) additive manufacturing. Due to my time as a machinist I have developed an intuition for competent design with manufacturing and production in mind. In terms of Additive Manufacturing, I spearheaded the implementation of a Stratasys Origin One Photopolymerization Machine, including the creation of brand new procedures to maximize part repeatability, a critical part of the prototyping work I did for the UCF Machine Shop. I received training directly from Stratasys to maintain and repair the machine and its local print server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the academic and professional lens, I like to spend my free time browsing for obsolete tech on eBay, playing guitar and reading. I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching myself computer and electrical engineering, in part because I feel a Mech/Aero Engineer in the 21st century should be somewhat competent in the computers that support everything we build, and in part because I&amp;rsquo;d like to know how to repair the stuff I buy on eBay. One of my ongoing projects involves a Tang Nano 9k FPGA dev board as a platform for learning digital logic design and Verilog HDL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-site&#34;&gt;The Site
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This website is proudly written with zero AI involvement. Extremely powerful tools or not, having to comb through documentation and Stack Overflow is an irreplaceable part of learning. I do NOT have a web dev background, so bear with me and my messy git history. Built on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, using the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/CaiJimmy/hugo-theme-stack-starter&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hugo Stack Theme&lt;/a&gt;. Immense thanks to people who put their code on the internet for our combined benefit. FOSS rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, whether this attracts employers or not, I just wanted to compile all the work I&amp;rsquo;ve done into one cohesive document. Documentation is paramount, and as much as I preach that, I&amp;rsquo;m terrible at writing things down unless required to. Putting this site together truly showed me how hard it is to recall the subtle details of work I&amp;rsquo;ve done being months removed from when things happened. I love this field, and much like a conventional garden is a product of love and care, this is my love note to engineering. Thank you for the visit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Photography</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/photography/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/photography/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/photography/scope.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Photography" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;equipment-background-and-other-thoughts&#34;&gt;Equipment, Background, and Other Thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started out with photography with a passed down Rebel T3. Not the latest or newest, but a perfectly capable sensor, well featured body, and it used the widely supported EF-S Canon mount. It allowed me to get my feet wet with the field, and besides, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to believe that having the newest, most expensive tool instantly makes you better at anything (to an extent). This applies to photography as well. Beyond quality of life features, a camera is a dark box with light input on one end and a light sensitive element on the other. In terms of image quality, improvements to digital sensors quickly became asymptotic for a casual photographer like me, so I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on learning about composition, color correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canondslr.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canondslr_hu_c02b7fc6b0af4a92.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/canondslr_hu_c631f2c39f8ef3ed.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Rebel T3 (Source: Canon USA)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time after, I came across a Rebel X SLR for extremely cheap. Most of the used film camera market orbits around a handful of critically acclaimed camera makes and models, and many well featured and advanced cameras tend to lurk in their shade. This specific camera appealed to the exact same market as the other Rebel, sporting an equally well balanced featureset catering to beginners. My favorite part about film is that the technology was essentially perfected by the end of the film era, so a majority of film cameras in the late 90s and early 00s share the exact same technology as DSLRs even to this day. Look at the very first DSLRs to hit the market; they are almost carbon copies of the final SLR models. My Rebel X is compatible with the exact same autofocus and metering system as my much newer DSLR, so it was as smooth of a transition into film as I could&amp;rsquo;ve wished for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canonslr.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;520&#34;
	height=&#34;414&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/canonslr_hu_b9a2f803acf96968.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/canonslr_hu_9005d7a4d89a51be.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Rebel X (Source: Canon USA)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;301px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through my fair share of rolls, I invested into a Pentax KX to learn photography down to a subconscious understanding of creative metering, composing, and to break the habit of treating the camera as a point and shoot. I began working at the film lab, which exposed me to what my peers felt and thought about the analog medium. Being forced to focus, think about what my aperture and shutter speed settings are doing in terms of the frame I am about to campture makes the images much more meaningful and connected to me as a photographer. Ansel Adams did not have the technology that we have within the latest Canon or Nikon flagships, yet he managed to create images so powerful as to encourage the appreciation of the beauty that spans the American continent, and the creation of the National Parks throughout the US. We live in an era where cameras are perpetually within reach in our pockets, yet it&amp;rsquo;s the most disconnected from photography I&amp;rsquo;ve felt. Pictures I take on my phone quickly fade into the depths of my camera roll, while the pictures I have taken on film all remain fresh in my psyche as the day I composed the shot through the viewfinder. The cherry on top is that the actual photons my camera saw at that instant are captured chemically to endure the years. Hard drives fail, servers and services shut down, yet grandpa&amp;rsquo;s Kodachrome slides from the 70s have withstood the test of time and will continue to do so. As technology advances, these masters have allowed us to reproduce mind bending quality from movies and TV recordings purely because they were stored chemically on film as opposed to magnetic tape or whatever other alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pentax.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1067&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pentax_hu_9f00f3aaa2066fa1.webp 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/pentax_hu_472fa4d104372817.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pentax KX (Source: 35MMC)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working as a developer with my background in engineering has made me appreciate the work of the thousands of people throughout centuries working to capture their lives. This ramble is a thinly veiled open love letter to the chemists, engineers, and designers at Kodak, Fujifilm, and the thousands of other companies that brought the ability to create snapshots of special moments to the masses. It moves me deeply that more and more people share this sentiment and are powering a film resurgence. I understand the purpose and the niche for digital photography, but the same way that one can choose to write something on paper versus typing it into a Word document, I believe film photography has an equal right to exist in the Internet era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of film photography, I get a little more in depth about the chemistry and construction of photographic film over in my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/&#34; &gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about my time as a film tech and the troubleshooting/repairing of some of our machines. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever sent out a roll to be developed and scanned, it&amp;rsquo;s a good behind-the-scenes view of why there&amp;rsquo;s delays and errors every once in a while. These are machines on life support with limited availability of replacement parts and plenty of lost knowledge from generations of engineers that retired at the beginning of the millenium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, see some of my favorites below. Thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-recent-shots&#34;&gt;My Favorite Recent Shots
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/scope.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;799&#34;
	height=&#34;530&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/scope_hu_a7894beeb31c1625.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/scope_hu_9696659eb8d648f0.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My Workstation&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;361px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/roots.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;679&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/roots_hu_2fb6918a913d8fcd.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/roots_hu_b71b3707cbf503b7.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Roots&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;66&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;159px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pigeons.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;679&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/photography/pigeons_hu_6d2af6430398ceda.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/photography/pigeons_hu_3792bc2a7e864085.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pigeons (a film point and shoot took this!)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;361px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Project SABR</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/rde.png" alt="Featured image of post Project SABR" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-achievements&#34;&gt;Major Achievements:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Developed a fully-fledged testing platform for air-breathing RDEs at UCF&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Laid the foundation for a future senior design teams&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Produced data for several AIAA SciTech 2025 papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rotating Detonation Engines (RDEs) are a relatively novel form of rocket propulsion that takes advantage of pressure-gain combustion. Conventional rocket engines use constant-pressure combustion cycles. RDEs theoretically produce better performance by taking better advantage of the energy stored chemically in the propellants. There is a fine line between detonating in the way that yields the performance advantage, and detonating in the way that destroys the engine. Due to the speeds involved in the process, these engines have only recently began gaining traction now that computers and sensors allow for the extremely fast sampling rates necessary for reliable data output. Their compact size and efficiency gains allow for storable propellants to be used more effectively in missile and defense applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals of this project at the beginning were beyond creating a working air breathing lab scale engine, to lay the foundation for further research to be done at UCF. This involved creating a test stand equipped with a capable and robust data acquisition system and control system. Considering the tight budget for a project of this ambition, it took a lot of creativity and clever thinking to get it off the ground (metaphorically).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ignition&#34;&gt;Ignition
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lighting an RDE involves precise timing and a strong enough relese of energy to induce a detonation mode within the engine. A fast burst (in tens of micro seconds) with not a lot of energy is more likely to induce a detonation compared to a longer burst with a ton more energy. Typically predets (short for predetonator tube) are used where an explosive mixture of gases are lit on one end of a long tube. Over this length of tube, the energy release is structured in such a way a shock is developed by the time the combusting gases exit. Due to the mechanism of operation, these have careful geometry that is hard to package into a system with compact and flight in mind. This is where my approach comes in, conventional torch. If the annulus can act as the constriction that focuses the energy towards a shock, the igniter can be more compact and allow for smaller designs for flight vehicles. After all, the annulus needs to already be able to contain and direct the energy to keep the detonation wave circling around the cavity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of both mechanical and electrical aspects of the ignition system. In terms of the mechanical side of things, I prioritized cost and ease of manufacturing over anything else, arriving at what is essentially a modified stainless steel 1/4 NPT cross fitting, as pictured below. The torch body is then connected to the rest of the RDE via a thick-walled stainless steel pipe nipple. I truly didn&amp;rsquo;t want the torch to be plagued by scope creep, so it incorporates as much stuff off the shelf as I could find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, the electrical system employs a standard car ignition coil, the cheapest I could find on Amazon. The circuit puts a 12V SPDT relay in purgatory by switching it rapidly between powering its own coil and pulsing the primary of the ignition coil. The best analog I could come up with was those &amp;ldquo;useless machine&amp;rdquo; desk toys where turning on the switch powers on the arm to turn itself off. The relay coil is wired to 12V via its Normally Closed contact in series with a momentary switch. When the switch is closed, the contact opens, powers it down, which allows it to return to rest and keep cycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/igniterschem.png&#34;
	width=&#34;805&#34;
	height=&#34;414&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/igniterschem_hu_190a446a7bf4096f.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/igniterschem_hu_fcc8fe21a8f0d90f.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Sparking Circuit Schematic (Sorry about quality, I need to dig for the original KiCAD project)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;194&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;466px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/torchintegrated.png&#34;
	width=&#34;672&#34;
	height=&#34;765&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/torchintegrated_hu_c8c9e58db900a0e4.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/torchintegrated_hu_ec13e46f6b6a86a7.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Torch as mounted on combustor&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;87&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;210px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I added a couple capacitors and resistors finetune exactly how long the charging and discharging takes in order to ensure the primary winding of the ignition coil has time to fully saturate before the power is switched off and the fields collapse to generate the high voltage out of the secondary. I could&amp;rsquo;ve gone with something based on a 555 timer or even more fancy, but circling back to that thought about scope creep, I truly just wanted it to work and work without needing to think about it. The only drawback is that mechanical relays really don&amp;rsquo;t like being switched that fast, and because the coil within the relay is also an inductor, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of arcing when it&amp;rsquo;s disconnected during the cycling. Adding a flyback diode across reduced the switching frequency so I arrived at the conclusion that relays are cheap enough to be consumable. During testing, the poor little relay did not fail or weld itself shut once, but if I were to be pulled back to the drawing board for a proper vehicle-born ignition system, I&amp;rsquo;d probably choose to go with something solid state or capacitor-based much like modern cars use for their sparking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;IMG_2053.mov&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;IMG_2053.mov&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cheeky extra feature I added to the torch is the presence of a pressure transducer line. During startup, the transducer would report the torch internal pressure, but once it&amp;rsquo;s powered down, it&amp;rsquo;d act as a CTAP (Capillary Tube Attenuated Pressure) readout for the annulus conditions. The transducer is coupled to the chamber via a 1/4&amp;quot; stainless steel tube to thermally isolate it from the extreme conditions during both startup and steady state operation. The length of tubing necessary was determined via the following function:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\begin{aligned}
\frac{T-T_{\inf}}{T_{0}-T_{\inf}}=\frac{1}{\cosh(\sqrt{\frac{4hD_{1}}{12k(D_{1}^{2}-D_{2}^{2})L}})}
\end{aligned}
\]&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$T$ = Maximum tolerable temperature at point of interest&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$T_{\inf}$ = Temperature of environment, taken as 100F for this analysis&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$T_{0}$ = Temperature of pressure source of interest, in this case, the estimated combustion temperature&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$L$ = Length of tubing, in inches&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$h$ = Heat transfer rate from tube to still air by natural convection, in BTU/hr/ft^2/F&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$D_{1}$ = outside diameter, in inches&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;$D_{2}$= inside diameter, in inches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model assumes the thin walled tube to be a fin following conduction and convection, much like a heatsink fin. The fin is expected to lose heat by convection at its end, and the pressure source is assumed to only transfer heat via the tube wall and through the pressure media. Another major assumption is that due to the thermal conductivity coefficient difference between the pressurized gas and the metallic walls of the tube, that the heat transfer via the stagnant gas is negligible. This leaves us with a tube length of around 8 inches. I ended up rounding up to 12 just in case we found anything extreme during testing and because the transducer was borrowed and VEEERY expensive. Please bear with me and the demonic US customary heat transfer calculation. I just like inches :^)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/quarterinchtubingstainlesscurve.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1105&#34;
	height=&#34;878&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/quarterinchtubingstainlesscurve_hu_c06829dac6633aa1.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/quarterinchtubingstainlesscurve_hu_91f56a4f06f33173.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Desmos Plot of the function. X axis is length of tube between source and transducer, Y axis is working fluid temperature&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;302px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, and because our entire operation relied on this very experimental approach working first try, I designed around being able to swap the torch out for a predet and still be able to use all propellant and control connections as normal. By keeping it as a drop-in replacement, we could quickly fall back on something that&amp;rsquo;s known to work properly and carry on with testing the combustor. There are so many unknowns in RDEs due to the technology&amp;rsquo;s low TRL that being able to rule out variables saves plenty of long nights of testing at the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, the concept of lighting the RDE was a lot easier said than done. I go more into detail about the outcome under &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#testing&#34; &gt;Testing&lt;/a&gt;, but the combination of a tight testing timeline, flawed assumptions in the annulus design, and the very experimental torch approach led to us switching it out to try and diagnose the combustor directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before pivoting towards my work in ignition, I helped with the first handful of iterations of the combustor. I focused on packaging and routing alongside my buddy Hunter, essentially figuring out how to efficiently route propellants from their respective ports coming from the fluids system and into the injectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we weighed the our options for manufacturing methods. We could push for an additively manufactured design, which would allow for complex geometry and reduce the number of critical seals to worry about, but had the drawback of very money, timeline, and risk intensive. On the other hand, we could go for something doable with the resources available at the UCF Machine Shop: reliable and free access to 3 and 5 axis machining, turning, EDM hole drilling and wire cutting. All we&amp;rsquo;d have to source is our required material. Regardless of whether we printed it or machined it conventionally, the RDE would be exposed to extreme conditions surrounding the detonation wave as it propagates, which means high pressures and temperatures sweeping around in a circle. Compared to a conventional engine, the cyclic failure modes began rearing their ugly head in all of our analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe_hu_7e021c70bed04496.gif 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe_hu_6b6678d8315ef4f4.gif 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Transient conditions within the combustor. Source: Wikipedia&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only saving grace was that the timescales for all this energy release were minuscule, although they compounded over time. Based on the fact we were targetting a very short runtime of only a couple seconds (and much more engineering analysis I will not go into here), we decided to go for 304 Stainless Steel. The reasoning came down to the fact we wanted the ability to fail and iterate without being dead in the water trying to source another brick of material to machine or a whole new printed part. Much of the research behind RDEs is uncharted territory, so even with all of our calculations and analysis double, triple, and quadruple checked, we wanted a large margin of safety on top of the ability to return to the drawing board and modify our design without crippling the project. So with all that being said, we settled on a conventionally manufactured combustor. From all the discussion, preliminary analysis, and talking to researchers both at UCF labs and across the US in places like Purdue and Johns Hopkins, we went for a modular design based on a stack of plates. Below are some of the first iterations of our combustor, initially by me and later modified by Hunter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE.png&#34;
	width=&#34;723&#34;
	height=&#34;838&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE_hu_c31bd0cecbc05a2e.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE_hu_dd98a65c6c29eab3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The First Assembly of the Project&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;86&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;207px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu.png&#34;
	width=&#34;626&#34;
	height=&#34;643&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu_hu_2a400445cfc86f5c.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu_hu_1746674ed0027766.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A section view better showing our initial plenum design&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;97&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;233px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount.png&#34;
	width=&#34;405&#34;
	height=&#34;297&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount_hu_f029b252b05fe1d3.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount_hu_f18d0d9e6e596db3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Combustor in context of its thrust-bearing mounting plate&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;136&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;327px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great start, but with any engineering project, we quickly started spotting flaws in terms of component integration, manufacturing, and especially in terms of final assembly in the stand. Looking back while writing this knowing how the project turned out as a whole makes the original design look extra alien. We moved away from fastening the inner body via a huge nut in the back, moved towards longitudinal fluid connections for both of the propellants, and most importantly, designed towards being able to fully assemble the combustor without needing the thrust plate. This last detail made it infinitely easier to mount and remove the combustor onto the test stand during testing. I truly don&amp;rsquo;t know what horrors we would&amp;rsquo;ve gone through if we needed the thrust plate involved while putting together everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the combustor consisted of an inner and outer body, nozzle cowl and spike, and the injector plate and backing plate. The inner and outer body constrain the annulus dimensions and their negative space form the cavity where the combustion occurs. The inner body, however, also acts as part of the internal plenum for one of the propellants. The selected injector schema is &amp;ldquo;Jet-in-Crossflow&amp;rdquo;. As the name implies, one of the propellants is injected perpendicular to the other. In our case, the hydrogen flows radially out from the inner body as the air is injected longitudinally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the nozzle spike and cowl, we decided on constricting the opening at the end of the annulus to raise the static pressure after the propellants are injected, as it has the effect of increasing detonability and aiding in ignition. It ensures propellants remain within the chamber for longer, which also helps the process overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rest-of-it&#34;&gt;The Rest Of It
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would love to keep writing much more about all that this project entailed, but it ultimately was a deeply intertwined group contribution. I am highlighting my direct work on getting this RDE off the ground, so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to any of my teammates to mention it all without also highlighting their achievements. A major part of senior design at UCF are these &amp;ldquo;Milestone Reports&amp;rdquo; where we, as a team, got together and tracked our work in a format similar to a design review. Milestone 6, the final one, contains a snapshot of the past year of our work leading up to the results we got and how we&amp;rsquo;d improve upon our work if we were to hypothetically continue testing after the semester ended. I feel it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to provide a curious reader, perhaps someone looking to base their research on our work, with the necessary in-depth info about the combustor, test stand, and our results. Please reach out to me directly if you have any questions. Email is best, all available over on the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/rdereport.pdf&#34; &gt;Here it is, weighing in at 134 pages.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go along with the report, I&amp;rsquo;d also like to provide a quick slidestack that we used to give an overview about the project. I can&amp;rsquo;t embed it as a .pptx, so unfortunately, gifs will not work on this version. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/showcaseslides.pdf&#34; &gt;Showcase Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to still cover what we experienced taking the design from a whiteboard/Solidworks to a real, working prototype. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be covering my contribution to our combined in-the-field problem solving and troubleshooting. Just know it&amp;rsquo;ll all be in a very simplified manner because, after all, we wrote that document precisely to act as a self-contained reference guide to our system. I might revisit this section and put together a quick rundown of our test stand, fluid system and DAQ and control electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing&#34;&gt;Testing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The testing campaign began with stress testing our control and data acquisition system by running the torch igniter over and over again. If we could pick out the bugs in our VIs, wiring, and sensors before moving onto the big leagues of trying to run the combustor with all the timings involved, we&amp;rsquo;d save a lot of pain and suffering down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The torch seemed promising on its own, however, no matter what we did it struggled to resist being blown out against the main propellant flow, so at this point we decided to pivot onto the predet and continue testing the combustor itself. Look at the predet in action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;IMG_3114.mov&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;IMG_3114.mov&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still weren&amp;rsquo;t getting any ignition at this point, so we returned to the drawing board. After combing through the footage and data gathered so far, we were led to the conclusion that two factors were in the way. A: the hydrogen jets coming out of the inner body struggled to penetrate the column of air being injected, contributing to terrible mixing and a suboptimal local equivalence ratio. Although the design total equivalence ratio was correct and it was confirmed by sensor data, the gases weren&amp;rsquo;t being mixed due to their extreme difference in velocities. At this point we decided to increase our injector pair count from 20 to 32, as this would decrease the relative mass flow of air per injector element and possibly alleviate these issues. Look below for one of the tests from the 2nd injector iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;C0052.mov&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;C0052.mov&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;C0048.mov&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;C0048.mov&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact this relatively simple fix is what leads me to believe that there&amp;rsquo;s still a possibility for the torch to work. I go into detail towards the end, but if the injector and mixing issues can be mitigated to the point the chamber conditions closely approximate the theoretical perfectly mixed propellant assumption, the torch would have an easier time starting a chain reaction culminating in a stable detonation. Ultimately, timelines didn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to get further testing time before graduating, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be keeping it in the backburner as I consider it novel enough to deserve further investigation and possibly a publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t set up back-end imaging until we confirmed we had reliable ignition, which pushed us into a time crunch to try and get the high speed camera allocated to us and set up properly. Unfortunately, we were unable to get a consistent setup stemming from some hardware issues on both the camera side of things and the mirror that allows it to look dead-on towards the exhaust. This left us with a handful of other ways to confirm operation, particularly, an increase in thrust compared to a cold-flow, and a pressure gain after ignition. Favorable data was present for both fields, but neither of these on their own could confirm whether the detonation mode was stable, how many waves were present, as well as other details about the environment within the annulus. As much as I trust our sensor data, I&amp;rsquo;m refraining from claiming we achieved detonation until we can have irrefutable evidence from studying chemoluminiscence within the combustor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on under the assumption we had a detonation mode, we varied the input pressures and timings in order to construct an operational map of the engine, telling us exactly what affected the behavior during startup and during steady state. To our surprise, pushing towards an extremely rich equivalence ratio actually improved the performance of the engine. I assume this is tied to our issues with local equivalence ratio, since more fuel being put in brings the local phi closer to the ideal range for hydrogen and air, and since the propellants aren&amp;rsquo;t fully mixed, the overall equivalence ratio matters much less in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-design-showcase&#34;&gt;Senior Design Showcase
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the milestone reports and other deliverables, senior design teams are expected to participate in the so-called Senior Design Showcase for the College of Engineering and Computer Science. Back in the day, it was a question of simply showing up to the event and talking to judges, but due to the growth of UCF&amp;rsquo;s Engineering program over the years, the showcase was split up into 2 phases. Phase 1 is the submission of a 10 minute video outlining your project goals, application, and approach to fulfill said goals. This video is then reviewed by the team&amp;rsquo;s assigned judges, and depending on the scores, it determines whether or not you progress to phase 2. If you&amp;rsquo;re selected to move on, you get to present your project at the showcase event where students, professors, and the judges get to see your display and directly hear you talk about your work of the past however many months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/srb3Dv_vAVQ&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure to lead the recording and editing of our video, as I happened to have the background in video editing necessary. I used my DVX100 camcorder to record about 3 hours of footage of our design, integration and testing as the project developed, all directly to tape and later digitized for non-linear video editing on Adobe Premiere. After wrapping up testing, my teammates and I sat down in the lab for about 8 hours combing through footage, gathering graphics and creating a rough outline to organize the flow of our thoughts. I had a great time turning this into a mind break from the cold engineering work and I hope you enjoy watching it as much as I did. It truly was the cherry on top to get to look back on our work summarized into a 10 minute video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts-and-acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts and Acknowledgements
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a section covering what we, as a team, would revisit and improve with our design. I&amp;rsquo;d like to highlight some of the flaws in our work and discuss some of what I&amp;rsquo;d do to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right off the bat, we came to the conclusion that our assumptions for post-injection pressure were a gross over-estimate. This led to our annulus thickness to be waaaay below what is needed for a stable detonation wave to propagate. In a nutshell, for a given propellant mixture, post-injection pressure and equivalent ratio, there&amp;rsquo;s a certain detonation cell size. The annulus has to allow a certain number of cells to reside within it in order for the detonation wave to proliferate. This should be the easier of the fixes, as the outer body inner diameter can be enlarged in order to accomodate the new size determined by our updated models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving onto the injectors, decreasing the distance between element pairs would also help with wave propagation. We started with 20 elements and during testing increased to 32. This greatly helped with ignition, but we still couldn&amp;rsquo;t achieve much more than rapid deflagration up to the cusp of a detonation mode. The spacing between the elements is still huge, and there&amp;rsquo;s not much forcing any mixing between them. If you think about the local equivalence ratio, you have a very well mixed environment directly at the injector element, degrading as you move radially towards the next element, acting much like speed bumps for the theoretical wave moving around. Slowing down and speeding up is disruptive while the combustion mode is still developing, so any reductions in inefficiencies would drastically improve the odds of detonation. This is still a fairly straight forward fix, but would require relocation of the ignition port. During the scope of senior design we did not end up stepping up in injector density, but the future work of some of my teammates as they move onto graduate research involves tackling this issue. The port can really be anywhere as long as it&amp;rsquo;s protected from the detonation front as it causes severe erosion to discontinuities in the flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The torch could be brought back into the mix if the conditions within the annulus can be improved, and possibly made more viable once we confirm operation of the combustor in general. However, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only problem with the torch. Hard starts and repeated use were very rough on the torch internals, particularly on the ceramic insulator around the spark plug. The layout currently has the plug electrode directly in the flow path of the two injectors to aid with ignition, but perhaps moving it a bit further towards the inner walls would help with thermal stresses and particularly percussive damage. Spark plugs are designed to take very high temperatures directly, but they&amp;rsquo;re fairly recessed within a cylinder and have better conduction paths to wick heat away. I also think that fine tuning ignition timing would greatly help prevent any further damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in terms of our experimental setup, we&amp;rsquo;d be able to get a lot higher quality data by adjusting a couple things about our test stand and particularly the load transfer onto the load cells. We used S-type load cells between the thrust plate attached to the rear of the combustor and the test stand chassis. The combustor weighs in at a very generous 20 lbs, which introduces some error from gravity pulling down on it and compressing some load cells and stretching the others. We did acknowledge this in design by adding a ball transfer support at the front that allowed the RDE to rest on something while still having very low friction in the direction of thrust, although it didn&amp;rsquo;t fully mitigate off axis loading. Additionally, the propellant soft lines we used for the connection between the RDE and the rest of the plumbing were very stiff, especially when pressurized, which transferred a non-negligible portion of the thrust to the plumbing, skewing our results. My solution would be to mount the entire main chassis on linear bearings, with the load cells being relocated to the connection between this chassis and the rest of the test stand. This would allow for the internal plumbing to be negligible and for the more flexible feed hoses coming from the tank farms to be the limiting factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, incorporating a better loadcell calibration approach would greatly help with the thrust data issues. Currently, we used a cable and pulley attached to the rear of the thrust plate with different weights attached to map out the load cell response. Moving onto something like a hydraulic cylinder would allow for a more continous dataset to be collected to calibrate the load cells, and would be a lot easier to control than having to load and unload gym weights from our pulley system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, for a project conceived and brought to fruition in less than a year, I&amp;rsquo;m extremely proud of the end product me and my teammates created and would love to eventually apply all these corrections. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll find more pain points to fix as I patch the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve just listed along with the many other listed in our report. After all, engineering is an iterative process. Solve one problem and 10 more appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank and congratulate Dr. Rezzag-Lebza, Dr. Burke, Dr. Stresau, and of course, my teammates. All our hard work paid off, and I hope we left a solid foundation for future detonation combustion research at UCF for both future senior design teams and researchers. Additionally, all the work before us that inspired the project as a whole: Fiorino, Dechert, among the many researchers across the US pioneering RDEs as a platform for future vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a machinist, I&amp;rsquo;d also like to highlight the crucial role that UCF&amp;rsquo;s Office of Research Machine Shop played in helping us not only bring the project to life, but also playing a role as a major contributor in optimizing the manufacturability of our system. The latter, along with their hard work, allowed us to achieve a quick turnaround between iterations. We were able to go from testing and reviewing data to firing a modified engine in the span of a week. Reader, remember to thank your manufacturing team as often as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>1. Theme Installation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/installation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/installation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Create a new hugo website or open your existing hugo site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;add-the-theme-to-your-hugo-site&#34;&gt;Add the theme to your hugo site
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use as a git submodule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme.git themes/digitalgarden
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone the repository (one-off, updating the theme may be harder later):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme.git themes/digitalgarden
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;package-lock.json&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tailwind.config.js&lt;/code&gt; files from the theme/digitalgarden folder to the root folder of your the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; to install required packages for theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm i -g postcss-cli&lt;/code&gt; to use PostCSS with Hugo build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set &lt;code&gt;theme = &#39;digitalgarden&#39;&lt;/code&gt; in config.toml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm run dev&lt;/code&gt; to start your local server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When deploying to services like Netlify or Vercel, use the following command for building your site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;npm i -g postcss-cli &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; npm run build
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/structure&#34; &gt;Understanding the theme structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>2. Structure</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/structure/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/structure/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Understand the structure of the theme&amp;rsquo;s setup to create content for your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;themes-content-structure&#34;&gt;Theme&amp;rsquo;s content structure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;11
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;12
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;13
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mysql&#34; data-lang=&#34;mysql&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;                 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Hosts all Markdown content
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;articles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Contains the list of markdown files for notes/posts
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;portfolio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;           &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# List of portfolio projects or case studies
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;md&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Test files (alternatively `spec` or `tests`)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;          &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Data used for rendering the list in Stack page
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that articles, portfolio and also stack pages require you to create &lt;code&gt;_index.md&lt;/code&gt; inside of it. Refer the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme/tree/main/exampleSite&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;exampleSite&lt;/a&gt; in theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these sections are optional and you can decide not to utilize those layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/primary-menu&#34; &gt;Configure Primary Menu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>3. Primary Menu</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/primary-menu/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/primary-menu/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sidebar of the theme uses the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; menu. Add all the items for your sidebar navigation in this menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;// config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;11
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;12
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;13
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Home&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Content&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Articles&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/articles&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;  Title of the menu item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt;  Path to navigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;  Used to decide the order of menu items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;params.header&lt;/code&gt;  Display menu item as header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the link points to an external website, the external icon is already displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using JSON or YAML formats? Check out the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/menus/#simple&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;menu&lt;/a&gt; documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/social-menu&#34; &gt;Configure Social Menu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>4. Social Menu</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/social-menu/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/social-menu/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The social menu can be used to configure all the social icons in the sidebar. Add links to your social media in the website config to show the icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Twitter&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;https://twitter.com&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; of the social menu needs to be unique and should be one of the supported values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supported values for the social menu item name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dribbble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codepen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/newsletter&#34; &gt;Configure newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>5. Newsletter</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/newsletter/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/newsletter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The theme supports a subscription to multiple newsletter providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buttondown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Substack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buttondown&#34;&gt;Buttondown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Params.newsletter.provider] = &amp;ldquo;buttondown&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy the &lt;code&gt;action&lt;/code&gt; url from your buttondown admin dashboard and add it to &lt;strong&gt;[Params.newsletter.path]&lt;/strong&gt; in config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.buttondown.email/img/9.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Buttondown share form URL&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;substack&#34;&gt;Substack
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Params.newsletter.provider] = &amp;ldquo;substack&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up substack is the easiest. Just add your substack newsletter URL (applicable for custom domains also) to &lt;strong&gt;[Params.newsletter.path]&lt;/strong&gt; in config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that since substack doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a native API for subscription. The theme uses the api from substackapi.com which is in no way associated to Substack itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revue&#34;&gt;Revue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add your revue &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; URL to &lt;code&gt;Params.newsletter.path&lt;/code&gt; in your config.toml. Once done, the newsletter widget will start showing up in website&amp;rsquo;s sidebar, allowing your visitors to subscribe to your newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-find-your-revue-url-to-use&#34;&gt;How to find your Revue URL to use
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Login to your Revue account and go to to &lt;code&gt;Account Settings&lt;/code&gt;, then the &lt;code&gt;Integrations&lt;/code&gt; tab. Scroll to the bottom, and click on &lt;code&gt;Learn more&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Signup forms&lt;/strong&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://downloads.intercomcdn.com/i/o/304891471/587879182e5d9d19aff97d2f/Screenshot&amp;#43;2021-02-26&amp;#43;at&amp;#43;9.10.32&amp;#43;AM.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Revue signup forms&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next page, you can find the add_subscriber URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme/blob/main/images/revue-signup-form-url.png?raw=true&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Revue URL&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy it and use in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/google-analytics&#34; &gt;Add Google analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>6. Google Analytics</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/google-analytics/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/google-analytics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital garden theme utilizes the Hugo&amp;rsquo;s [internal template](internal templates) for Google analytics and so both Google analytics v3 and GA v4 (gtag) are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add your &lt;strong&gt;UA-PROPERTY_ID&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;G-MEASUREMENT_ID&lt;/strong&gt; to config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-analytics-v3-analyticsjs&#34;&gt;Google Analytics v3 (analytics.js)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;googleAnalytics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;UA-PROPERTY_ID&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-analytics-v4-gtagjs&#34;&gt;Google Analytics v4 (gtag.js)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;googleAnalytics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;G-MEASUREMENT_ID&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/metatags&#34; &gt;Configure Metatags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>7. Metatags</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/metatags/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/metatags/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Metatags are used to provide additional information about the page, usually used by search engines and social media websites / apps. It allows to customize your page&amp;rsquo;s title, description, preview image and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-default-tags&#34;&gt;Configure default tags
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;// config.toml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Personal Digital Garden&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;My Digital Garden on the Internet&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/digital-garden-logo.png&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting the above values will be used as default for all pages unless its overridden in a specific page&amp;rsquo;s markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;customize-specific-pages-tags&#34;&gt;Customize specific page&amp;rsquo;s tags
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the markdown file of the page for which you need to customize the tags and set the following properties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;// custom-page.md&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34; data-lang=&#34;toml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Custom Page&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;My Custom page in the Digital Garden&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/custom-page.png&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These values will be used for open graph tags and twitter cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34;&gt;
If you like this theme, support by sharing it with friends on Twitter  &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Digital%20Garden%20theme%20for%20Hugo%0Ahttps%3A//github.com/apvarun/digital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;inline&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter URL&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/url?style=social&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fapvarun%2Fdigital-garden-hugo-theme&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design1/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Croissant orange croissant dolor orange croissant. Lollipop biscuit donut vanilla sweet croissant. Apple donut candy tiramisu cream jelly. Croissant sweet cookie vanilla tiramisu dolor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange. Candy sweet cookie sweet donut marzipan. Vanilla cookie sprinkles pastry orange cookie. Marzipan donut ipsum sugar biscuit vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy cookie muffin pastry lollipop vanilla. Apple orange tiramisu jelly ipsum sugar. Candy cake orange ipsum orange muffin. Sugar pastry orange cream orange pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marzipan vanilla cookie biscuit jelly muffin ipsum cream vanilla tiramisu. Marzipan vanilla sweet tiramisu pastry cake jelly jelly pastry cake. Cookie sweet donut candy pastry apple dolor orange lollipop biscuit. Muffin cream ipsum ipsum sprinkles sugar tiramisu pastry sweet tiramisu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Cream sugar apple donut apple croissant</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design2/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tiramisu sprinkles marzipan lollipop marzipan dolor. Jelly candy marzipan vanilla candy ipsum. Sugar croissant lollipop vanilla cream marzipan. Sprinkles croissant cream dolor jelly marzipan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange. Candy sweet cookie sweet donut marzipan. Vanilla cookie sprinkles pastry orange cookie. Marzipan donut ipsum sugar biscuit vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy cookie muffin pastry lollipop vanilla. Apple orange tiramisu jelly ipsum sugar. Candy cake orange ipsum orange muffin. Sugar pastry orange cream orange pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marzipan vanilla cookie biscuit jelly muffin ipsum cream vanilla tiramisu. Marzipan vanilla sweet tiramisu pastry cake jelly jelly pastry cake. Cookie sweet donut candy pastry apple dolor orange lollipop biscuit. Muffin cream ipsum ipsum sprinkles sugar tiramisu pastry sweet tiramisu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Apple cream vanilla apple marzipan muffin</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design3/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/design3/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tiramisu sprinkles marzipan lollipop marzipan dolor. Jelly candy marzipan vanilla candy ipsum. Sugar croissant lollipop vanilla cream marzipan. Sprinkles croissant cream dolor jelly marzipan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastry jelly cookie sugar donut orange. Candy sweet cookie sweet donut marzipan. Vanilla cookie sprinkles pastry orange cookie. Marzipan donut ipsum sugar biscuit vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy cookie muffin pastry lollipop vanilla. Apple orange tiramisu jelly ipsum sugar. Candy cake orange ipsum orange muffin. Sugar pastry orange cream orange pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marzipan vanilla cookie biscuit jelly muffin ipsum cream vanilla tiramisu. Marzipan vanilla sweet tiramisu pastry cake jelly jelly pastry cake. Cookie sweet donut candy pastry apple dolor orange lollipop biscuit. Muffin cream ipsum ipsum sprinkles sugar tiramisu pastry sweet tiramisu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Links</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/links/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/links/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To use this feature, add &lt;code&gt;links&lt;/code&gt; section to frontmatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page&amp;rsquo;s frontmatter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;GitHub is the world&amp;#39;s largest software development platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;https://github.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/logos_page/GitHub-Mark.png&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;TypeScript is a typed superset of JavaScript that compiles to plain JavaScript.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;https://www.typescriptlang.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;l&#34;&gt;ts-logo-128.jpg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;image&lt;/code&gt; field accepts both local and external images.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
