<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Electronics on Arturo Negrette</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/electronics/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Electronics on Arturo Negrette</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/electronics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Project SABR</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/rde.png" alt="Featured image of post Project SABR" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-achievements&#34;&gt;Major Achievements:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Developed a fully-fledged testing platform for air-breathing RDEs at UCF&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Laid the foundation for a future senior design teams&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Produced data for several AIAA SciTech 2025 papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rotating Detonation Engines (RDEs) are a relatively novel form of rocket propulsion that takes advantage of pressure-gain combustion. Conventional rocket engines use constant-pressure combustion cycles. RDEs theoretically produce better performance by taking better advantage of the energy stored chemically in the propellants. There is a fine line between detonating in the way that yields the performance advantage, and detonating in the way that destroys the engine. Due to the speeds involved in the process, these engines have only recently began gaining traction now that computers and sensors allow for the extremely fast sampling rates necessary for reliable data output. Their compact size allows for storable propellants to be used more effectively in missile and defense applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals of this project at the beginning were beyond creating a working air breathing lab scale engine, to lay the foundation for further research to be done at UCF. This involved creating a test stand equipped with a capable and robust data acquisition system and control system. With the tight budget for a project of this ambition we had to get creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ignition&#34;&gt;Ignition
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lighting an RDE involves precise timing and a strong enough relese of energy to induce a detonation mode within the engine. A fast burst (in tens of micro seconds) with not a lot of energy is more likely to induce a detonation compared to a longer burst with a ton more energy. Typically predets are used where an explosive mixture of gases are lit on one end of a long tube and over that length of tube the energy release is structured in such a way a shock is developed by the time the combusting gases exit. Due to the mechanism of operation, these have careful geometry that is hard to package into a system with compact and flight in mind. This is where my approach comes in, conventional torch. If the annulus can act as the constriction that focuses the energy towards a shock, the igniter can be more compact and allow for smaller designs for flight vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of both mechanical and electrical aspects of the ignition system. In terms of the mechanical side of things, I prioritized cost and ease of manufacturing over anything else, arriving at what is essentially a modified stainless steel 1/4 NPT cross fitting, as pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The torch body is then connected to the rest of the RDE via a thick-walled stainless steel pipe nipple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, the concept of lighting the RDE was a lot easier said than done. I go more into detail about the outcome under Testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before pivoting towards my work in ignition, I helped with the first handful of iterations of the combustor. I focused on packaging and routing alongside my buddy Hunter, essentially figuring out how to efficiently route propellants from their respective ports coming from the fluids system and into the injectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we weighed the our options for manufacturing methods. We could push for an additively manufactured design, which would allow for complex geometry and reduce the number of critical seals to worry about, but had the drawback of very money, timeline, and risk intensive. On the other hand, we could go for something doable with the resources available at the UCF Machine Shop: reliable and free access to 3 and 5 axis machining, turning, EDM hole drilling and wire cutting. All we&amp;rsquo;d have to source is our required material. Regardless of whether we printed it or machined it conventionally, the RDE would be exposed to extreme conditions surrounding the detonation wave as it propagates, which means high pressures and temperatures sweeping around in a circle. Compared to a conventional engine, the cyclic failure modes began rearing their ugly head in all of our analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe.gif&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe_hu_7e021c70bed04496.gif 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/waveswipe_hu_6b6678d8315ef4f4.gif 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Transient conditions within the combustor. Source: Wikipedia&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only saving grace was that the timescales for all this energy release were minuscule, although they compounded over time. Based on the fact we were targetting a very short runtime of only a couple seconds (and much more engineering analysis I will not go into here), we decided to go for 304 Stainless Steel. The reasoning came down to the fact we wanted the ability to fail and iterate without being dead in the water trying to source another brick of material to machine or a whole new printed part. Much of the research behind RDEs is uncharted territory, so even with all of our calculations and analysis double, triple, and quadruple checked, we wanted a large margin of safety on top of the ability to return to the drawing board and modify our design without crippling the project. So with all that being said, we settled on a conventionally manufactured combustor. From all the discussion, preliminary analysis, and talking to researchers both at UCF labs and across the US in places like Purdue and Johns Hopkins, we went for a modular design based on a stack of plates. Below are some of the first iterations of our combustor, initially by me and later modified by Hunter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE.png&#34;
	width=&#34;723&#34;
	height=&#34;838&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE_hu_c31bd0cecbc05a2e.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyIterationOfRDE_hu_dd98a65c6c29eab3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The First Assembly of the Project&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;86&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;207px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu.png&#34;
	width=&#34;626&#34;
	height=&#34;643&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu_hu_2a400445cfc86f5c.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/OtherViewEarlyu_hu_1746674ed0027766.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A section view better showing our initial plenum design&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;97&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;233px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount.png&#34;
	width=&#34;405&#34;
	height=&#34;297&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount_hu_f029b252b05fe1d3.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/project-sabr/EarlyMount_hu_f18d0d9e6e596db3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Combustor in context of its thrust-bearing mounting plate&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;136&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;327px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great start, but with any engineering project, we quickly started spotting flaws in terms of component integration, manufacturing, and especially in terms of final assembly in the stand. Looking back while writing this knowing how the project turned out as a whole makes the original design look extra alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plate design after ruling out 3d printing due to timeline and thankfully tariffs confirmed out option&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to route taps for pressure and igniter channel using conventional machining methods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rest-of-it&#34;&gt;The Rest Of It
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would love to keep writing much more about all that this project entailed, but it ultimately was a deeply intertwined group contribution. I am highlighting my direct work on getting this RDE off the ground, so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to any of my teammates to mention it all without also highlighting their achievements. A major part of senior design at UCF are these &amp;ldquo;Milestone Reports&amp;rdquo; where we, as a team, got together and tracked our work in a format similar to a design review. Milestone 6, the final one, contains a snapshot of the past year of our work leading up to the results we got and how we&amp;rsquo;d improve upon our work if we were to hypothetically continue testing after the semester ended. I feel it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to provide a curious reader, perhaps someone looking to base their research on our work, with the necessary in-depth info about the combustor, test stand, and our results. Please reach out to me directly if you have any questions. Email is best, all available over on the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/rdereport.pdf&#34; &gt;Here it is, weighing in at 134 pages.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go along with the report, I&amp;rsquo;d also like to provide a quick slidestack that we used to give an overview about the project. I can&amp;rsquo;t embed it as a .pptx, so unfortunately, gifs will not work on this version. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/showcaseslides.pdf&#34; &gt;Showcase Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to still cover what we experienced taking the design from a whiteboard/Solidworks to a real, working prototype. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be covering my contribution to our combined in-the-field problem solving and troubleshooting. Just know it&amp;rsquo;ll all be in a very simplified manner because, after all, we wrote that document precisely to act as a self-contained reference guide to our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing&#34;&gt;Testing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-design-showcase&#34;&gt;Senior Design Showcase
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/srb3Dv_vAVQ&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts-and-acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts and Acknowledgements
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thicker annulus, overestimated pressures, ignition may be easier with the torch, testing necessary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;things id fix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;better thrust calibration, possibly using a pneumatic/hydraulic cylinder to calibrate load cells&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;less rigid plumbing, alternatively, put the whole thrust bearing frame on linear bearings, measure thrust there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank and congratulate Dr. Rezzag-Lebza, Dr. Burke, Dr. Stresau, and of course, my teammates. All our hard work paid off, and I hope we left a solid foundation for future detonation combustion research at UCF for both future senior design teams and researchers. Additionally, all the work before us that inspired the project as a whole: Fiorino, Dechert, among the many researchers across the US pioneering RDEs as a platform for future vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a machinist, I&amp;rsquo;d also like to highlight the crucial role that UCF&amp;rsquo;s Office of Research Machine Shop played in helping us not only bring the project to life, but also playing a role as a major contributor in optimizing the manufacturability of our system. The latter, along with their hard work, allowed us to achieve a quick turnaround between iterations. We were able to go from testing and reviewing data to firing a modified engine in the span of a week. Reader, remember to thank your manufacturing team as often as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to Cope with Being a Film Lab Tech</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post How to Cope with Being a Film Lab Tech" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working at a film lab for the last couple of months, and the engineering degree immediately made itself useful by giving me the tools to keep some of these machines alive. Problems ranging from just corrosion within a sensor&amp;rsquo;s connector to open heart surgery on a board no longer made. For a glorified sous-vide tank, the Noritsu engineers put a lot of safeguards and smart engineering in place to keep these working as well as they have for as long as they have. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this article with the intention of logging whatever I find for whoever takes over for me, or whoever finds this website in similar despair as I have googled whenever something broke. There&amp;rsquo;s also the nice side effect of showing off the stuff between my ears to employers. Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1581&#34;
	height=&#34;1655&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines_hu_40e4bf388d6e5b95.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Machines_hu_6afb7710e738d341.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;V50 (larger), V30 (smaller)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;229px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the V50, relatively sophisticated MiniLab unit for C-41 Color Development. Short Leader style, which means you tape the film to a sheet of plastic with sprocket holes on it, and that&amp;rsquo;s what drags the film itself out of the can and into each step of the development process. The 50 in V50 stands for 50 rolls an hour, so not too shabby accounting for the fact a 36 exposure roll of film tends to be somewhere around 5 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to put the rest of the machine in context, let&amp;rsquo;s cover the development steps of Black and White and C-41 film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both, the film is coated with silver halide crystals. Exactly how they are spread on the film and what they do during and after the development process varies between B/W, C-41, and every other development process available, but the working principle remains the same. After being exposed to light, these crystals are raised to a higher energy level, leaving a latent image stored chemically on the film emulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2560&#34;
	height=&#34;784&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing_hu_c1aa083cf5197cde.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/Photographic_processing_hu_f284969c6be4a63e.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Essential Steps of Development (Source:Wikipedia)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;326&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;783px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B/W:
-Developer: This step converts the latent image contained in the activated silver halide into metallic silver. This metallic silver only appears in the locations where light struck the emulsion. The stronger the light, the more concentrated the silver, the darker or &amp;ldquo;denser&amp;rdquo; the image is at this location, and the reverse applies as well. All of this to say that we now have a negative image of what was captured in the camera at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Fixer: After the developer, the image that matters to us is created. However, it&amp;rsquo;s still surrounded by the inactive silver halides still in the emulsion. No light, no developer action, no metallic silver. The fixer can dissolve the halides but not metallic silver, which allows us to selectively remove the unused stuff and keep our image negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy stuff, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing monochrome stuff essentially as long as we have been able to reliably understand organic chemistry. B/W film made a year ago and 80 years ago work the exact same, and excluding the effects of age, can be developed the exact same way. Color, however, is where modernity truly shines through. Kudos to all the chemists and engineers that allowed us to record the world around us in more than shadows and highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure.png&#34;
	width=&#34;960&#34;
	height=&#34;520&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure_hu_ffca95b32759b63b.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/SuperiaStructure_hu_fe242140875926.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Superia Emulsion Cross-Section (Source:Wikipedia)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;184&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;443px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C-41:
-Developer: Still does the same as B/W, with the caveat that now the dye couplers (part that creates the colors) are activated and create the dyes of each layer. Fun fact, you can cross-process any C-41 roll as B/W, you just ignore the color couplers for a monochrome image. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to salvage pictures from obsolete C-22 rolls from 60+ years ago. Hard drives fail, files go corrupt, but in a decently wide range of conditions, chemistry prevails. Cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Bleach: Due to the layout of a typical C-41 film emulsion, after development, you now have both a dye-based image, and the metallic silver image. Keeping both of these leads to super dense images with low saturation, and often it was used intentionally as a color grading effect in movies and TV in a method called &amp;ldquo;bleach bypass&amp;rdquo;. The bleach attacks this metallic image and converts it back to silver halides, which can now be removed by the fixer. It also helps reducing the density of the dyes in the film base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Fixer: Same as B/W. Fixer actually holds quite a decent amount of silver, so it&amp;rsquo;s very important to dispose of properly and feed it to silver reclaiming facilities. Not that any other chemical is great for carelessly dumping into the environment, but the fixer carries metals with it that are specially bad to introduce into an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Stabilizer: The dyes contained on each layer are technically not fixed in space, and age, environmental factors, and improper handling of the film can lead to them migrating between layers. The end effect is a reduction in the color reproduction quality, so stabilizers are used to &amp;ldquo;lock&amp;rdquo; the dyes out of escaping their layer. You can very well skip this step if you are just looking for a glorified Instagram filter, but in order to produce negatives that can withstand the test of time, stabilization is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to get into detail about the careful design of color emulsions, but so have another 500 trillion people on the internet, so I will unfortunately not elaborate here. Google it, watch Tech Connections about it, don&amp;rsquo;t use this case of brevity as an excuse to avoid learning about film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our machine feeds the leader card and the film it&amp;rsquo;s attached to into a very deep 18 Liter Color Developer (CD) tank at a speed that allows for each length of film to be in contact with the CD solution, while automatically adding a replenishment amount of fresh chemical to account for exhaustion per roll. All the chemicals involved in these reactions are disposable and need to be replenished accounting for the surface area that passes through. The film is continued to be carried in and out of the solutions automagically by careful mechanical design of roller transports like conveyors through a factory. The machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually know where this film is, but it vaguely knows when it started being fed and when the canister was cut off at the end, and it knows how fast everything is spinning and moving the film along. So it starts counting and can make an educated guess as to where it&amp;rsquo;d be and what chemicals would be exhausted at which times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, it passes through essentially a gentler air fryer before being released fully dry for it to be scanned and/or sleeved for preservation. Almost magical coming from my background of hanging up film from my shower curtain loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1466&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50_hu_8b0122298ca19550.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/v50_hu_aecb27f69d67701.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Noritsu QSF-V30&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;109&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;261px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected to mention much about the modified V30 that develops B/W, but it&amp;rsquo;s the same principles and same tech, just behaving differently to accomodate for the different chemistry. Both operate the same. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-recent-color-developer-working-tank-overheating&#34;&gt;Most Recent: Color Developer Working Tank Overheating
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;symptoms&#34;&gt;Symptoms:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermitent S-Sol Thermo Activated Error&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution reaches 43C before other safeguards kick in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially only happened during overnight sleep cycle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Initial Troubleshooting:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared thermocouple readings to thermometer in working tank and in side tank (will elaborate on tank layout in a second)
&amp;ndash; Temp Matches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drained tank, cleaned agitation and recirculation pumps
&amp;ndash; Minor to Negligible Improvement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context, we had just recovered from the below problem of the cutter jamming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I came back to the machine, I noticed that although the troubleshooting LEDs on the machine showed the control unit was not powering the heater relay, temperature continued to climb. Coming from the car background, tapping around with the rubber back of a screwdriver didn&amp;rsquo;t help. Turns out SSR stands for Solid State Relay, something I realized pretty late, embarassingly late. The awesome engineers at Noritsu had the foresight of including redundant relays on the board, or rather, populating relay footprints for heater circuits not used in this machine model. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the V100 or the V5Billion use these relays, but I&amp;rsquo;m lucky mine doesn&amp;rsquo;t because these exact P/Ns are looooooong discontinued. In my panic before realizing there were spares I did find a suitable drop-in replacement. Here&amp;rsquo;s the link in case you&amp;rsquo;re not so lucky to have a relay cache on your board.  I would like the record to show that I called it early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World&amp;rsquo;s oldest solder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1_hu_93685407cdf85bae.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard1_hu_fbf845d356c5dfa3.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Board in Question&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2160&#34;
	height=&#34;2874&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2_hu_aabeb9fefb297485.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/PowerBoard2_hu_91867f1fcb2743c8.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Mounted on the V50&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;75&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;180px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2160&#34;
	height=&#34;2518&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit_hu_c669376e8c07f439.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/TheCulprit_hu_1e1e222c1419b654.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Culprit&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;85&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;205px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2_hu_df908385250d6428.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/noritsu-v50/BurntPad2_hu_6b638e8e042fbeb5.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Where I found It&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah. Looking at the board closer would&amp;rsquo;ve saved quite a bit of time. If you noticed the missing pad, you try to babysit a board like this into releasing a component and tell me how it goes. It&amp;rsquo;s like they glued it on like a postage stamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cutter-jams&#34;&gt;Cutter Jams
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;symptoms-1&#34;&gt;Symptoms:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right Lane Struggled to Cut Canister at the End of the roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canisters stuck after cutting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutter Return Error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-troubleshooting-1&#34;&gt;Initial Troubleshooting
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
